<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Adventures in JavaScript Development]]></title>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-28T20:14:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://rmurphey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Murphey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Baseline for Front-End [JS] Developers: 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/03/23/a-baseline-for-front-end-developers-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-23T21:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/03/23/a-baseline-for-front-end-developers-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been almost three years since I wrote <a href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/12/a-baseline-for-front-end-developers/">A Baseline for Front-End Developers</a>, probably my most popular post ever. Three years later, I still get Twitter mentions from people who are discovering it for the first time.</p>

<p>In some ways, my words have aged well: there is, shockingly, nothing from that 2012 post that has me hanging my head in shame. Still, though: three years is a long time, and a whole lot has changed. In 2012 I encouraged people to learn browser dev tools and get on the module bandwagon; CSS pre-processors and client-side templating were still worthy of mention as new-ish things that people might not be sold on; and JSHint was a welcome relief from the #getoffmylawn admonitions &#8211; accurate though they may have been &#8211; of JSLint.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s 2015. I want to write an update, but as I sit down to do just that, I realize a couple of things. One, it&#8217;s arguably not fair to call this stuff a &#8220;baseline&#8221; &#8211; if you thought that about the original post, you&#8217;ll find it doubly true for this one. One could argue we should consider the good-enough-to-get-a-job skills to be the &#8220;baseline.&#8221; But there are a whole lot of front-end jobs to choose from, and getting one doesn&#8217;t establish much of a baseline. For me, I don&#8217;t want to get a job; I want to get invited to great jobs. I don&#8217;t want to go to work; I want to go to work with talented people. And I don&#8217;t want to be satisfied with knowing enough to do the work that needed to be done yesterday; I want to know how to do the work that will need to get done tomorrow.</p>

<p>Two, my world has become entirely JavaScript-centric: knowledge of the ins and outs of CSS has become less and less relevant to my day-to-day work, except where performance is concerned. I know there are plenty of very smart front-end developers for whom this isn&#8217;t true, but I have also noticed a growing gulf between those who focus on CSS and those who focus on JavaScript. That&#8217;s probably a subject for another blog post, but I bring it up just to say: I am woefully unequipped to make recommendations about what you should know about CSS these days, so I&#8217;m not going to try.</p>

<p>In short: if this list of things doesn&#8217;t fit your vision of the front-end world, that&#8217;s OK! We&#8217;re both still good people. Promise.</p>

<h2>JavaScript</h2>

<p>Remember back in 2009 when you read that HTML5 would be ready to use in 2014, and that seemed like a day that would never come? If so, you&#8217;re well prepared for the slow-but-steady emergence of ES6 (which is now called <a href="https://esdiscuss.org/topic/javascript-2015">ES2015</a>, a name that is sure to catch on any day now), the next version of JavaScript. Getting my bearings with ES6 &#8211; er, ES2015 &#8211; is hands-down my biggest JavaScript to-do item at the moment; it is going to be somewhere between game-changing and life-altering, what with classes, real privacy, better functions and arguments, <code>import</code>-able modules, and so much more. Those who are competent and productive with the new syntax will have no trouble standing out in the JS community. Required reading:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://leanpub.com/understandinges6/read/">Understanding ES6</a>, a work-in-progress book being developed in the open by Nicholas Zakas.</li>
<li><a href="http://babeljs.io/">BabelJS</a>, a tool that lets you write ES6 today and &#8220;compile&#8221; it to ES5 that will run in current browsers. They also have a good <a href="http://babeljs.io/docs/learn-es6/">learning</a> section.</li>
<li><a href="http://es6rocks.com/">ES6 Rocks</a>, with various posts that explore ES6 features, semantics, and gotchas.</li>
</ul>


<p>Do you need to be an ES6/ES2015 expert? Probably not today, but you should know at least as much about it as your peers, and possibly more. It&#8217;s also worth at least entertaining the possibility of writing your next greenfield project using ES6; the future will be here before you know it.</p>

<p>New language features aside, you should be able to speak fluently about the asynchronicity of JavaScript, and using callbacks and promises to manage it. You should have well-formed opinions about strategies for loading applications in the browser and communicating between pieces of an application. You should maybe have a favorite application development framework, but not at the expense of having a general understanding of how other frameworks operate, and the tradeoffs you accept when you choose one.</p>

<h2>Modules &amp; Build Tools</h2>

<p>There&#8217;s no debate that modules should be the building blocks of client-side web applications. Back in 2012, there was lots of debate about what <em>kind</em> of modules we should use for building apps destined for the browser &#8211; <a href="https://github.com/amdjs/amdjs-api/blob/master/AMD.md">AMD</a> or <a href="http://webpack.github.io/docs/commonjs.html">CommonJS</a>. The somewhat-gross <a href="https://github.com/umdjs/umd">UMD</a> wrapper arose to try to avoid answering the question while still allowing code reuse &#8211; because hey, what&#8217;s a few more bytes between friends?</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t feel like this debate is anywhere near resolved, but this is the area where I feel like we&#8217;ve seen the largest transformation since my 2012 article, though perhaps that&#8217;s a reflection of my personal change of heart. I&#8217;m not ready to say that I&#8217;m done with AMD, but let&#8217;s just say I&#8217;m floored by how practical it has become to develop and deploy web applications using CommonJS, including modules imported with <code>npm</code>.</p>

<p>With much love for all that <a href="http://requirejs.org/">RequireJS</a> has contributed to the module conversation, I&#8217;m a bit enamored of <a href="http://webpack.github.io/">webpack</a> right now. Its features &#8211; such as easy-to-understand build flags &#8211; feel more accessible than RequireJS. Its hot-swap builds via its built-in dev server make for a fast and delightful development story. It doesn&#8217;t force an AMD vs. CommonJS decision, because it supports both. It also comes with a ton of loaders, making it fairly trivial to do lots of common tasks. <a href="http://browserify.org/">Browserify</a> is worth knowing about, but lags far behind Webpack in my opinion. Smart people I trust tell me that <a href="https://github.com/systemjs/systemjs">systemjs</a> is also a serious contender in this space, but I haven&#8217;t used it yet, and its docs leave me wanting. Its companion package manager <a href="http://jspm.io/">jspm</a> is intriguing, allowing you to pull in modules from multiple sources including npm, but I&#8217;m a bit wary of combining those two concerns. Then again, I never thought I&#8217;d break up with AMD, yet here I seem to be, so we&#8217;ll see.</p>

<p>I still long for a day when we stop having module and build tool debates, and there is a single module system and sharing code between arbitrary projects becomes realistic and trivial without the overhead of UMD. Ideally, the arrival of <a href="http://www.2ality.com/2014/09/es6-modules-final.html">ES6 modules</a> will bring that day &#8211; and transpilers will fill in the gaps as the day draws closer &#8211; but I find it just as likely that we&#8217;ll keep finding ways to make it complicated.</p>

<p>In the meantime, front-end developers need to have an opinion about at least a couple of build tools and the associated module system, and that opinion should be backed up by experience. For better or worse, JavaScript is still in a state where the module decision you make will inform the rest of your project.</p>

<h2>Testing</h2>

<p>Testing of client-side code has become more commonplace, and a few new testing frameworks have arrived on the scene, including <a href="http://karma-runner.github.io/0.12/index.html">Karma</a> and <a href="https://theintern.github.io/">Intern</a>. I find Intern&#8217;s promise-based approach to async testing to be particulary pleasing, though I confess that I still write most of my tests using <a href="http://mochajs.org/">Mocha</a> &#8211; sometimes I&#8217;m just a creature of habit.</p>

<p>The main blocker to testing is the code that front-end devs tend to write. I gave a talk toward the end of 2012 about <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OzjogCFO4Zo">writing testable JavaScript</a>, and followed up with an <a href="http://alistapart.com/article/writing-testable-javascript">article</a> on the topic a few months later.</p>

<p>The second biggest blocker to testing remains the tooling. Webdriver is still a huge pain to work with. Continuous automated testing of a complex UI across all supported browsers continues to be either impossible, or so practically expensive that it might as well be impossible &#8211; and never mind mobile. We&#8217;re still largely stuck doing lightweight automated functional tests on a small subset of supported browser/device/OS combinations, and leaning as hard as we can on lower-level tests that can run quickly and inexpensively. This is a bummer.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in improving the problem of untested &#8211; or untestable &#8211; code, the single most valuable book you can read is <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Working-Effectively-Legacy-Michael-Feathers/dp/0131177052">Working Effectively with Legacy Code</a>. The author, Michael Feathers, defines &#8220;legacy code&#8221; as any code that does not have tests. On the topic of testing, the baseline is to accept the truth of that statement, even if other constraints are preventing you from addressing it.</p>

<h2>Process Automation</h2>

<p>You, hopefully, take for granted the existence of <a href="http://gruntjs.com/">Grunt</a> for task automation. <a href="http://gulpjs.com/">Gulp</a> and <a href="http://broccolijs.com/">Broccoli</a> provide a different approach to automating builds in particular. I haven&#8217;t used Broccoli, and I&#8217;ve only dabbled in Gulp, but I&#8217;ve definitely come to appreciate some of the limitations of Grunt when it comes to automating complex tasks that depend on other services &#8211; especially when that task needs to run thousands of times a day.</p>

<p>The arrival of <a href="http://yeoman.io/">Yeoman</a> was a mere 45 days away when I wrote my 2012 post. I confess I didn&#8217;t use it when it first came out, but recently I&#8217;ve been a) starting projects from scratch using unfamiliar tech; and b) trying to figure out how to standardize our approach to developing third-party JS apps at Bazaarvoice. Yeoman really shines in both of these cases. A simple <code>yo react-webpack</code> from the command line creates a whole new project for you, with all the bells and whistles you could possibly want &#8211; tests, a dev server, a hello world app, and more. If React and Webpack aren&#8217;t your thing, there&#8217;s probably a generator to meet your needs, and it&#8217;s also easy to create your own.</p>

<p>Given that Yeoman is a tool that you generally use only at the start of a project, and given that new projects don&#8217;t get started all the time, it&#8217;s mostly just something worth knowing about. Unless, of course, you&#8217;re also trying to standardize practices across projects &#8211; then it might be a bit more valuable.</p>

<p>Broccoli has gotten its biggest adoption as the basis for ember-cli, and  folks I trust suggest that pairing may get a makeover &#8211; and a new name &#8211; to form the basis of a Grunt/Yeoman replacement in the future. Development on both Grunt and Yeoman has certainly slowed down, so it will be interesting to see what the future brings there.</p>

<h2>Code Quality</h2>

<p>If you, like me, start to twitch when you see code that violates a project&#8217;s well-documented style guide, then tools like <a href="http://jscs.info/">JSCS</a> and <a href="http://eslint.org/">ESLint</a> are godsends, and neither of them existed for you to know about them back in 2012. They both provide a means to document your style guide rules, and then verify your code against those rules automatically, before it ever makes it into a pull request. Which brings me to &hellip;</p>

<h2>Git</h2>

<p>I don&#8217;t think a whole lot has changed in the world of Git workflows since 2012, and I&#8217;d like to point out Github <em>still</em> hasn&#8217;t made branch names linkable on the pull request page, for f@#$s sake.</p>

<p>You should obviously be comfortable working with feature branches, rebasing your work on the work of others, squashing commits using interactive rebase, and doing work in small units that are unlikely to cause conflicts whenever possible. Another Git tool to add to your toolbox if you haven&#8217;t already is the ability to run hooks &#8211; specifically, pre-push and pre-commit hooks to run your tests and execute any code quality checks. You can write them yourself, but tools like <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/ghooks">ghooks</a> make it so trivial that there&#8217;s little excuse not to integrate them into your workflow.</p>

<h2>Client-Side Templating</h2>

<p>This may be the thing I got the most wrong in my original post, for some definition of &#8220;wrong.&#8221; Client-side templating is still highly valuable, of course &#8211; so valuable that it will be built-in to ES2015 &#8211; but there can be too much of a good thing. It&#8217;s been a hard-earned lesson for lots of teams that moving all rendering to the browser has high costs when it comes to performance, and thus has the &#8220;generate all the HTML client-side&#8221; approach rightfully fallen out of favor. Smart projects are now generating HTML server-side &#8211; maybe even pre-generating it, and storing it as static files that can be served quickly &#8211; and then &#8220;hydrating&#8221; that HTML client-side, updating it with client-side templates as events warrant.</p>

<p>The new expectation here &#8211; and I say this to myself as much as to anyone else &#8211; is that you are considering the performance implications of your decisions, and maybe not restricting yourself quite so thoroughly to the realm of the browser. Which, conveniently, leads to &hellip;</p>

<h2>Node</h2>

<p>You say you know JavaScript, so these days I expect that you can hop on over to the Node side of things and at least pitch in, if not get at least knee-deep. Yes, there are file systems and streams and servers &#8211; and some paradigms that are fundamentally different from front-end dev &#8211; but front-end developers who keep the back end at arm&#8217;s length are definitely limiting their potential.</p>

<p>Even if your actual production back-end doesn&#8217;t use Node, it&#8217;s an invaluable tool when it comes to keeping you from getting blocked by back-end development. At the very least, you should be familiar with how to <a href="https://docs.npmjs.com/cli/init">initialize a Node project</a>; how to set up an <a href="http://expressjs.com/">Express</a> server and routes; and how use the <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/request">request</a> module to proxy requests.</p>

<h2>The End</h2>

<p>Thanks to Paul, Alex, Adam, and Ralph for their thorough review of this post, and for generously pointing out places where I could do better. Thank them for the good parts, and blame any errors on me.</p>

<p>With that, good luck. See you again in another three years, perhaps.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing Conference Proposals]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/01/26/writing-conference-proposals/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-26T21:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/01/26/writing-conference-proposals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve had several <a href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/01/11/office-hours/">office hours</a> sessions in the last couple of weeks, and one topic that comes up again and again is how to write a talk description.</p>

<p>If you think about it, conference organizers don&#8217;t have a whole lot to go on when they&#8217;re choosing talks, unless they already know who you are. Even if your name is well-known, though, organizers may still not know who you are &#8211; lots of conferences are taking a <a href="http://weareallaweso.me/for_curators/">blind approach</a> to selecting speakers. That means that no matter who you are, your talk description might be the only thing organizers have on which to base their decision. When you give your talk, you&#8217;ll need to engage your audience; the abstract is your chance to engage the organizer.</p>

<p>After answering the question several times, I&#8217;ve realized that I have a pretty explainable &#8211; some might call it formulaic &#8211; approach to writing abstracts for a certain common type of talk. It works well for talks about how you solved a problem, talks about how you came to learn a thing you didn&#8217;t know, and even &#8220;10 things you didn&#8217;t know about X&#8221; talks. I thought I&#8217;d try to explain it here.</p>

<h2>Paragraph 1: The context</h2>

<p>The first paragraph is where you set the scene, and make it clear to your reader that they have been in the situation you&#8217;re going to talk about. This is where you establish a connection, baiting a hook that you&#8217;ll set later.</p>

<blockquote><p>You&#8217;ve got the hang of this whole JavaScript thing. Your code works on ancient browsers, and positively sings on new ones. AMD, SPA, MVC &#8211; you can do that stuff in your sleep.</p></blockquote>

<h2>Paragraph 2: Well, actually &#8230;</h2>

<p>The second paragraph is where you break the bad news, which savvy readers may already know: the thing you laid out in the first paragraph is more complicated than it seems, or has downsides that people don&#8217;t realize, or generally is a bad approach &#8230; but only with the benefit of hindsight, which you just happen to have.</p>

<blockquote><p>But now your users are trying to type in your Very Important Form, and nothing is showing up; that widget that&#8217;s supposed to end up in a certain div is showing up somewhere completely different; and, rarely but not never, your app just doesn&#8217;t load at all. You <em>thought</em> you had the hang of this whole JavaScript thing, but now you&#8217;re in the world of third-party JavaScript, where all you control is a single script tag and where it&#8217;s all but impossible to dream up every hostile environment in which your code will be expected to work. &#8220;It works on my machine&#8221; has never rung quite so hollow.</p></blockquote>

<h2>Paragraph 3: The promise</h2>

<p>You&#8217;ve successfully induced a bit of anxiety in your reader &#8211; and a strong desire to know what they don&#8217;t know. The hook is set, so the last paragraph is the time to promise to relieve that anxiety &#8211; but only if your talk is chosen!</p>

<blockquote><p>In this talk, we&#8217;ll take a look at some of the delightful bugs we&#8217;ve had to solve at Bazaarvoice while working on the third-party JavaScript app that collects and displays ratings and reviews for some of the world&#8217;s largest retailers. We&#8217;ll also look at some strategies for early detection &#8211; and at some scenarios where you are just plain SOL.</p></blockquote>

<h2>Next</h2>

<p>It turns out that in the process of writing your abstract, you&#8217;ve also written the most basic outline for your talk: on stage, you&#8217;ll want to set the context, explain the complexity, then deliver on your promise. Pretty handy, if you ask me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Office Hours for Aspiring Speakers]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/01/11/office-hours/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-11T21:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2015/01/11/office-hours</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m expecting that my 2015 is going to include a bit less speaking than in years past, so I&#8217;m hoping I can use some of that newly available time to help new speakers find their way to the stage. To that end, I&#8217;m kicking off &#8220;office hours&#8221; this week: a few slots a week where aspiring and up-and-coming speakers can borrow my ear for a bit to talk about their ideas, their fears, their questions, and their ambitions.</p>

<p>This idea isn&#8217;t mine; I was inspired by a similar effort by <a href="http://jenmyers.net/mentoring/">Jen Myers</a>, who has been offering mentoring sessions to aspiring speakers since 2013. I&#8217;m forever indebted to the folks who helped me get through my first talk, and I&#8217;ve been honored to give a gentle nudge to several other speakers in the years since.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested, you can <a href="http://calendly.com/rmurphey/office-hours">sign up here</a>. There&#8217;s no script or agenda, and &#8211; at least to start with &#8211; I&#8217;m not going to try to suggest who should or shouldn&#8217;t sign up. If you think it would be useful to you, go for it! My only ask is that you be seriously interested in giving coherent, informative, engaging talks on technical topics.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing Unit Tests for Existing JavaScript]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2014/07/13/unit-tests/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-13T21:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2014/07/13/unit-tests</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My team at <a href="http://www.bazaarvoice.com/careers/">Bazaarvoice</a> has been spending a lot of time lately thinking about quality and how we can have greater confidence that our software is working as it should.</p>

<p>We&#8217;ve long had functional tests in place that attempt to ask questions like &#8220;When a user clicks a button, will The Widget do The Thing?&#8221; These tests tell us a fair amount about the state of our product, but we&#8217;ve found that they&#8217;re brittle &#8211; even after we abstracted away the CSS selectors that they rely on &#8211; and that they take approximately forever to run, especially if we want to run them in all of the browsers we support. The quality of the tests themselves is all over the map, too &#8211; some of them are in fact unit tests, not really testing anything <em>functional</em> at all.</p>

<p>A few months ago we welcomed a new QA lead to our team as part of our renewed focus on quality. Having a team member who is taking a thoughtful, systematic approach to quality is a game-changer &#8211; he&#8217;s not just making sure that new features work, but rather has scrutinized our entire approach to delivering quality software, to great effect.</p>

<p>One of the things he has repeatedly emphasized is the need to push our tests down the stack. Our functional tests should be black-box &#8211; writing them shouldn&#8217;t require detailed knowledge of how the software works under the hood. Our unit tests, on the other hand, should provide broad and detailed coverage of the actual code base. In an ideal world, functional tests can be few and slow-ish, because they serve as an infrequent smoke test of the application; unit tests should be thorough, but execute quickly enough that we run them all the time.</p>

<p>Until now, our unit tests have been entirely focused on utility and framework code &#8211; do we properly parse a URL, for example? &#8211; not on code that&#8217;s up close and personal with getting The Widget to do The Thing. I&#8217;d told myself that this was fine and right and good, but in reality I was pretty terrified of trying to bolt unit tests onto feature code of incredibly varying quality, months or even years after it was first written.</p>

<p>A week or so ago, thanks to some coaxing/chiding from fellow team members, I decided to bite the bullet and see just how bad it would be. A week later, I feel like I&#8217;ve taken the first ten steps in a marathon. Of course, taking those first steps involves making the decision to run, and doing enough training ahead of time that you don&#8217;t die, so in that regard I&#8217;ve come a long way already. Here&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve done and learned so far.</p>

<h3>Step 0</h3>

<p>I was lucky in that I wasn&#8217;t starting entirely from scratch, but if you don&#8217;t already have a unit testing framework in place, don&#8217;t fret &#8211; it&#8217;s pretty easy to set up. We use <a href="http://gruntjs.com/">Grunt</a> with <a href="http://visionmedia.github.io/mocha/">Mocha</a> as our test framework and <a href="https://github.com/LearnBoost/expect.js/">expect.js</a> as our assertion library, but if I were starting over today I&#8217;d take a pretty serious look at <a href="http://theintern.io/">Intern</a>.</p>

<p>Our unit tests are organized into suites. Each suite consists of a number of files, each of which tests a single AMD module. Most of the modules under test when I started down this path were pretty isolated &#8211; they didn&#8217;t have a ton of dependencies generally, and had very few runtime dependencies. They didn&#8217;t interact with other modules that much. Almost all of the existing unit test files loaded a module, executed its methods, and inspected the return value. No big deal.</p>

<p>Feature-related code &#8211; especially already-written feature-related code &#8211; is a different story. Views have templates. Models expect data. Models pass information to views, and views pass information to models. Some models need parents; others expect children. And pretty much everything depended on a global-ish message broker to pass information around.</p>

<p>Since the code was originally written without tests, we are guaranteed that it would be in various states of testability, but a broad rewrite for testability is of course off the table. We&#8217;ll rewrite targeted pieces, but doing so comes with great risk. For the most part, our goal will be to write tests for what we have, then refactor cautiously once tests are in place.</p>

<p>We decided that the first place to start was with models, so I found the simplest model I could:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;framework/bmodel&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;underscore&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">BModel</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">BModel</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">extend</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">options</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{},</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">name</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;mediaViewer&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">init</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">config</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">options</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">extend</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">options</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">options</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Why do we have a model that does approximately nothing? I&#8217;m not going to attempt to answer that, though there are Reasons &#8211; but for the sake of this discussion, it certainly provides an easy place to start.</p>

<p>I created a new suite for model tests, and added a file to the suite to test the model. I could tell you that I naively plowed ahead thinking that I could just load the module and write some assertions, but that would be a lie.</p>

<h3>Mocking: Squire.js</h3>

<p>I knew from writing other tests, on this project and projects in the past, that I was going to need to &#8220;mock&#8221; some of my dependencies. For example, we have a module called <code>ENV</code> that is used for &#8230; well, way too much, though it&#8217;s better than it used to be. A large portion of <code>ENV</code> isn&#8217;t used by any given module, but <code>ENV</code> itself is required by essentially every model and view.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/iammerrick/Squire.js/">Squire.js</a> is a really fantastic library for doing mocking in RequireJS-land. It lets you override how a certain dependency will be fulfilled; so, when a module under test asks for <code>'ENV'</code>, you can use Squire to say &#8220;use this object that I&#8217;ve hand-crafted for this specific test instead.&#8221;</p>

<p>I created an Injector module that does the work of loading Squire, plus mocking a couple of things that will be missing when the tests are executed in Node-land.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;squire&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;jquery&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">Squire</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="k">typeof</span> <span class="nb">window</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;undefined&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">injector</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">Squire</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;_BV&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">mock</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;jquery&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">mock</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;window&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="p">{};</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">else</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">injector</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">Squire</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Next, I wired up the test to see how far I could get without mocking anything. Note that the main module doesn&#8217;t actually load the thing we&#8217;re going to test &#8211; first, it sets up the mocks by calling the <code>injector</code> function, and then it uses the created injector to require the module we want to test. Just like a normal <code>require</code>, the <code>injector.require</code> is async, so we have to let our test framework know to wait until it&#8217;s loaded before proceeding with our assertions.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;test/unit/injector&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">injector</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">describe</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;MediaViewer Model&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">before</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">done</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">require</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="s1">&#39;bv/c2013/model/mediaViewer&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">M</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">M</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">done</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">it</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;should be named&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">m</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span><span class="p">({});</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">m</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">name</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;mediaViewer&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">it</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;should mix in provided options&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">m</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span><span class="p">({},</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">foo</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;bar&#39;</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">m</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">options</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">foo</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;bar&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This, of course, still failed pretty spectacularly. In real life, a model gets instantiated with a component, and a model also expects to have access to an <code>ENV</code> that has knowledge of the component. Creating a &#8220;real&#8221; component and letting the &#8220;real&#8221; <code>ENV</code> know about it would be an exercise in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7s664NsLeFM">inventing the universe</a>, and this is exactly what mocks are for.</p>

<p>While the &#8220;real&#8221; <code>ENV</code> is a Backbone model that is instantiated using customer-specific configuration data, a much simpler <code>ENV</code> suffices for the sake of testing a model&#8217;s functionality:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;backbone&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">Backbone</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">opts</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">mock</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;ENV&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">ENV</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">Backbone</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Model</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">componentManager</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nx">find</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">opts</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">component</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">ENV</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Likewise, a &#8220;real&#8221; component is complicated and difficult to create, but the pieces of a component that this model needs to function are limited. Here&#8217;s what the component mock ended up looking like:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;underscore&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">settings</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">settings</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="p">{};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">features</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">features</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="p">[];</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">trigger</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{},</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">hasFeature</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">refName</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">featureName</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">contains</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">features</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">featureName</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">getScope</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;scope&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">contentType</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">contentType</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">componentId</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">id</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">views</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>In the case of both mocks, we&#8217;ve taken some dramatic shortcuts: the real <code>hasFeature</code> method of a component is a lot more complicated, but in the component mock we create a <code>hasFeature</code> method whose return value can be easily known by the test that uses the mock. Likewise, the behavior of the <code>componentManager</code>&#8217;s <code>find</code> method is complex in real life, but in our mock, the method just returns the same thing all the time. Our mocks are designed to be configurable by &#8211; and predictable for &#8211; the test that uses it.</p>

<p>Knowing what to mock and when and how is a learned skill. It&#8217;s entirely possible to mock something in such a way that a unit test passes but the actual functionality is broken. We actually have pretty decent tests around our real component code, but not so much around our real <code>ENV</code> code. We should probably fix that, and then I can feel better about mocking <code>ENV</code> as needed.</p>

<p>So far, my approach has been: try to make a test pass without mocking anything, and then mock as little as possible after that. I&#8217;ve also made a point of trying to centralize our mocks in a single place, so we aren&#8217;t reinventing the wheel for every test.</p>

<p>Finally: when I first set up the injector module, I accidentally made it so that the same injector would be shared by any test that included the module. This is bad, because you end up sharing mocks across tests &#8211; violating the &#8220;only mock what you must&#8221; rule. The injector module shown above is correct in that it returns a function that can be used to create a new injector, rather than the injector itself.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what the final MediaViewer test ended up looking like:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
<span class='line-number'>38</span>
<span class='line-number'>39</span>
<span class='line-number'>40</span>
<span class='line-number'>41</span>
<span class='line-number'>42</span>
<span class='line-number'>43</span>
<span class='line-number'>44</span>
<span class='line-number'>45</span>
<span class='line-number'>46</span>
<span class='line-number'>47</span>
<span class='line-number'>48</span>
<span class='line-number'>49</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// This properly sets up Squire and mocks window and jQuery</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// if necessary (for running tests from the command line).</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;test/unit/injector&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// This is a function that mocks the ENV module.</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;test/unit/mocks/ENV&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// This is a function that mocks a component.</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;test/unit/mocks/component&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">ENVMock</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">component</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">injector</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// This will become the constructor for the model under test.</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// Create an object that can serve as a model&#39;s component.</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">c</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">component</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// We also need to mock the ENV module and make it aware of</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// the fake component we just created.</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">ENVMock</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">component</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">c</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">describe</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;MediaViewer Model&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">before</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">done</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">require</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="s1">&#39;bv/c2013/model/mediaViewer&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">M</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">M</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">done</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">it</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;should be named&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">m</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">component</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">c</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">},</span> <span class="p">{});</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">m</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">name</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;mediaViewer&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">it</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;should mix in provided options&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">m</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">MediaViewer</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">component</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">c</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">},</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">foo</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;bar&#39;</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">m</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">options</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">foo</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;bar&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Spying: Sinon</h3>

<p>After my stunning success with writing 49 lines of test code to test a 13-line model, I was feeling optimistic about testing views, too. I decided to tackle this fairly simple view first:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;framework/bview&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;underscore&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;hbs!contentAuthorProfileInline&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;mf!bv/c2013/messages/avatar&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;bv/util/productInfo&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;framework/util/bvtracker&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;util/specialKeys&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">BView</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">template</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">msgPack</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">ProductInfo</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">BVTracker</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">specialKeys</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">BView</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">extend</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">name</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;inlineProfile&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">templateName</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;contentAuthorProfileInline&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">events</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="s1">&#39;click .bv-content-author-name .bv-fullprofile-popup-target&#39;</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;launchProfile&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">template</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">template</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">msgpacks</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">msgPack</span><span class="p">],</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">launchProfile</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">e</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="c1">// use r&amp;r component outlet to trigger full profile popup component event</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">getTopModel</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">trigger</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="s1">&#39;showfullprofile&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">model</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Author&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">BVTracker</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">feature</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">type</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Used&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">name</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Click&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">detail1</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;ViewProfileButton&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">detail2</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;AuthorAvatar&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">bvProduct</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">ProductInfo</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">getType</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">),</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">productId</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">ProductInfo</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">getId</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>It turned out that I needed to do the same basic mocking for this as I did for the model, but this code presented a couple of interesting things to consider.</p>

<p>First, I wanted to test that <code>this.getTopModel().trigger(...)</code> triggered the proper event, but the <code>getTopModel</code> method was implemented in <code>BView</code>, not the code under test, and without a whole lot of gymnastics, it wasn&#8217;t going to return an object with a <code>trigger</code> method.</p>

<p>Second, I wanted to know that <code>BVTracker.feature</code> was getting called with the right values, so I needed a way to inspect the object that got passed to it, but without doing something terrible like exposing it globally.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://sinonjs.org">Sinon</a> and its <a href="http://sinonjs.org/docs/#spies">spies</a>. Spies let you observe methods as they are called. You can either let the method still do its thing while watching how it is called, or simply replace the method with a spy.</p>

<p>I solved the first problem by defining my own <code>getTopModel</code> method on the model instance, and having it return an object. I gave that object a <code>trigger</code> method that was actually just a spy &#8211; for the sake of my test, I didn&#8217;t care what trigger <em>did</em>, only how it was called. Other tests [will eventually] ensure that triggering this event has the desired effect on the targeted model, but for the sake of this test, we don&#8217;t care.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what the test looks like:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">describe</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;#launchProfile&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">spy</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">v</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">before</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">spy</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">sinon</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">spy</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">v</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nx">InlineProfile</span><span class="p">({</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="c1">// model and component are defined elsewhere</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">component</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">component</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">model</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">model</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">model</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Author&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;author&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">v</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">getTopModel</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="k">return</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">trigger</span> <span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">spy</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">it</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;should trigger showfullprofile event on top model&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">v</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">launchProfile</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">spy</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">lastCall</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">args</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">]).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;showfullprofile&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">spy</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">lastCall</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">args</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">]).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;author&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I solved the second problem &#8211; the need to see what&#8217;s getting passed to <code>BVTracker.feature</code> &#8211; by creating a <code>BVTracker</code> mock where every method is just a spy:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="c1">// This is a mock for BVTracker that can be used by unit tests.</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nx">define</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;underscore&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">],</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">opts</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">BVTracker</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">{};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">injector</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">mock</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;framework/util/bvtracker&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">_</span><span class="p">([</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="s1">&#39;error&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="s1">&#39;pageview&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="s1">&#39;feature&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">]).</span><span class="nx">each</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">event</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">BVTracker</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="nx">event</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">sinon</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">spy</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">BVTracker</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>My test looked at the <code>BVTracker.feature</code> spy to see what it got when the view&#8217;s <code>launchProfile</code> method was called:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">it</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;should send a feature analytics event&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">v</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">launchProfile</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">evt</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">BVTracker</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">feature</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">lastCall</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">args</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">];</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">evt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">type</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Used&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">evt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">name</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Click&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">evt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">detail1</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;ViewProfileButton&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">evt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">detail2</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;AuthorAvatar&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">evt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">bvProduct</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;RatingsAndReviews&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">expect</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">evt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">productId</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">to</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">equal</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;product1&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">});</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I&#8217;ve barely touched on what you can do with spies, or with Sinon in general. Besides providing simple spy functionality, Sinon delivers a host of functionality that makes tests easier to write &#8211; swaths of which I haven&#8217;t even begun to explore. One part I have explored is its ability to create fake XHRs and to fake whole servers, allowing you to test how your code behaves when things go wrong on the server. Do yourself a favor and spend some time reading through the excellent <a href="http://sinonjs.org/docs/">docs</a>.</p>

<h3>What to test &#8230; and not</h3>

<p>I&#8217;ve written tests now for a tiny handful of models and views. Setting up the mocks was a bit of a hurdle &#8211; and there were plenty of other hurdles that are too specific to our project for me to talk about them in detail &#8211; but overall, the hardest part has been figuring out what, exactly, to test. I crafted the examples above to be pretty straightforward, but reality is a lot more complicated.</p>

<p>Writing tests for existing code requires first understanding the code that&#8217;s being tested and identifying interesting moments in that code. If there&#8217;s an operation that affects the &#8220;public&#8221; experience of the module &#8211; for example, if the value of a model attribute changes &#8211; then we need to write a test that covers that operation&#8217;s side effect(s). If there&#8217;s code that runs conditionally, we need to test the behavior of that code when that condition is true &#8211; and when it&#8217;s not. If there are six possible conditions, we need to test them all. If a model behaves completely differently when it has a parent &#8211; and this happens far too often in our code &#8211; then we need to simulate the parent case, and simulate the standalone case.</p>

<p>It can be tempting to try to test the implementation details of existing code &#8211; and difficult to realize that you&#8217;re doing it even when you don&#8217;t mean to. I try to stay focused on testing how other code might consume and interact with the module I&#8217;m testing. For example, if the module I&#8217;m testing triggers an event in a certain situation, I&#8217;m going to write a test that proves it, because some other code is probably expecting that event to get triggered. However, I&#8217;m not going to test that a method of a certain name gets called in a certain case &#8211; that&#8217;s an implementation detail that might change.</p>

<p>The exercise of writing unit tests against existing code proves to be a phenomenal incentive to write better code in the future. One comes to develop a great appreciation of methods that have return values, not side effects. One comes to loathe the person &#8211; often one&#8217;s past self &#8211; who authored complex, nested conditional logic. One comes to worship small methods that do exactly one thing.</p>

<p>So far, I haven&#8217;t rewritten any of the code I&#8217;ve been testing, even when I&#8217;ve spotted obvious flaws, and even when rewriting would make the tests themselves easier to write. I don&#8217;t know how long I&#8217;ll be able to stick to this; there are some specific views and models that I know will be nearly impossible to test without revisiting their innards. When that becomes necessary, I&#8217;m hoping I can do it incrementally, testing as I go &#8211; and that our functional tests will give me the cover I need to know I haven&#8217;t gone horribly wrong.</p>

<h3>Spreading the love</h3>

<p>Our team&#8217;s next step is to widen the effort to get better unit test coverage of our code. We have something like 100 modules that need testing, and their size and complexity are all over the map. Over the coming weeks, we&#8217;ll start to divide and conquer.</p>

<p>One thing I&#8217;ve done to try to make the effort easier is to create a scaffolding task using Grunt. Running <code>grunt scaffold-test:model:modelName</code> will generate a basic file that includes mocking that&#8217;s guaranteed to be needed, as well as the basic instantiation that will be required and a couple of simple tests.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s another senior team member who has led an effort in the past to apply unit tests to an existing code base, and he&#8217;s already warned me to expect a bit of a bumpy road as the team struggles through the inevitable early challenges of trying to write unit tests for existing feature code. I expect there to be a pretty steep hill to climb at first, but at the very least, the work I&#8217;ve done so far has &#8211; hopefully &#8211; gotten us to the top of the vertical wall that had been standing in our way.</p>

<h3>Further Reading</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m not exactly the first person to write about this. You may find these items interesting:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3476054/can-unit-testing-be-successfully-added-into-an-existing-production-project-if-s">On adding unit tests to existing code</a></li>
<li><a href="http://programmers.stackexchange.com/questions/207401/writing-tests-for-existing-code">On whether it&#8217;s worth the effort</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0131177052">Working Effectively with Legacy Code</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Austin]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2014/01/01/austin/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T19:03:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2014/01/01/austin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In August 2002, it was a little more than a year since I&#8217;d left my job at my hometown newspaper. I had just sold my car and left my two jobs as a bartender. Between the tips in my pocket and the money I&#8217;d made from selling my car &#8211; a 1996 Neon with a probably cracked head gasket &#8211; I had about $2,000 to my name. I had a bicycle, camping gear, cooking gear, maps, a handheld GPS, a flip phone, two changes of bicycle clothing, and two changes of street clothes. I was in Camden, Maine, and my parents were taking my picture in front of a bicycle shop.</p>

<iframe src="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rdmey/3147066467/player/ed302f4534" height="213" width="320"  frameborder="0" allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>My destination was Austin. My plan was to ride to Savannah, GA &#8211; via Boston, New York, and the eastern shore of Maryland &#8211; and then turn right. I didn&#8217;t really have much of a plan beyond that, except that I hoped to crash with a friend of a friend when I got to Austin. I heard they had a good bus system. I figured I could sort out a job before my money ran out.</p>

<p>Three weeks and 1,000 miles later, I found myself outside of New Bern, NC, more tan and more fit than I&#8217;d ever been or would ever be again. I stopped at a grocery store and picked up food for the evening, tying a bag of apples off the side of my bike. I was planning to camp just south of town, but as I neared a park in the center of town, I  found myself surrounded by cyclists setting up camp. They were there for a fund-raising ride, and no, no one would mind if I camped in the park with them instead of riding another 10 miles.</p>

<p>I pitched my tent. I followed them to the free dinner being served for them across the street.</p>

<p>I rode 150 miles &#8211; unencumbered by camping gear and all the rest &#8211; in the fund-raising ride for the next two days.</p>

<p>I made new friends. They invited me to come stay with them for a few days in Chapel Hill.</p>

<p>I lived with them for a month. I borrowed their 1990 Ford Festiva for a year.</p>

<p>I got a job painting a house. I got a job waitressing. I got a job doing desktop publishing. I got a job making web sites.</p>

<p>I got good at JavaScript. I traveled the world talking about it.</p>

<p>I met a girl. We bought a house. We adopted a baby.</p>

<p>I never made it to Austin, though life has taken me there a few days at a time more times than I can count. Finally, in 2013, I even got a job there. Since February, I&#8217;ve made the trek enough times that it&#8217;s truly become a home away from home. I&#8217;ve stopped using my phone to find my way around. Waitresses recognize me. People tell me about the secret back way to work, but I already know it. I have opinions about breakfast tacos.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s time to finish the story I started more than a decade ago, which brings me to the point: With much love for Durham, and for the irreplaceable people who have made our lives so full here, we&#8217;re moving to Austin this spring. At last.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refactoring setInterval-based polling]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2013/02/04/refactoring-setInterval-polling/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T15:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2013/02/04/refactoring-setInterval-polling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across some code that looked something like this the other day, give or take a few details.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">checkSyncStatus</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">))</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="k">return</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">check</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">ajax</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;/sync_status&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">dataType</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;json&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">success</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">resp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">resp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">status</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;done&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">reloadUser</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nx">clearInterval</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">));</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">null</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">setInterval</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">check</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="p">));</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">};</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The code comes from an app whose server-side code queries a third-party service for new data every now and then. When the server is fetching that new data, certain actions on the front-end are forbidden. The code above was responsible for determining when the server-side sync is complete, and putting the app back in a state where those front-end interactions could be allowed again.</p>

<p>You might have heard that <code>setInterval</code> can be a dangerous thing when it comes to polling a server*, and, looking at the code above, it&#8217;s easy to see why. The polling happens every 1000 seconds, <em>whether the request was successful or not</em>. If the request results in an error, or fails, or takes more than 1000 milliseconds, <code>setInterval</code> doesn&#8217;t care &#8211; it will blindly kick off another request. The interval only gets cleared when the request succeeds and the sync is done.</p>

<p>The first refactoring for this is easy: switch to using <code>setTimeout</code>, and only enqueue another request once we know what happened with the previous one.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">checkSyncStatus</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">))</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="k">return</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">check</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">ajax</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;/sync_status&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">dataType</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;json&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">success</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">resp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">resp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">status</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;done&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">reloadUser</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">null</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nx">setTimeout</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">check</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">true</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">};</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now, if the request fails, or takes more than 1000 milliseconds, at least we won&#8217;t be perpetrating a mini-DOS attack on our own server.</p>

<p>Our code still has some shortcomings, though. For one thing, we aren&#8217;t handling the failure case. Additionally, the rest of our application is stuck looking at the <code>syncCheck</code> property of our <code>App</code> object to figure out when the sync has completed.</p>

<p>We can use a promise to make our function a whole lot more powerful. We&#8217;ll return the promise from the function, and also store it as the value of our <code>App</code> object&#8217;s <code>syncCheck</code> property. This will let other pieces of code respond to the outcome of the request, whether it succeeds or fails. With a simple guard statement at the beginning of our function, we can also make it so that the <code>checkSyncStatus</code> function will return the promise immediately if a status check is already in progress.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">checkSyncStatus</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">syncCheck</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">get</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">syncCheck</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">syncCheck</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">dfd</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Deferred</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">dfd</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">promise</span><span class="p">());</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">success</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">resp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">resp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">status</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;done&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">reloadUser</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">dfd</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">resolve</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">null</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">setTimeout</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">check</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">fail</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">dfd</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">reject</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">set</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;syncCheck&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">null</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">check</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">req</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">ajax</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;/sync_status&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">dataType</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s1">&#39;json&#39;</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">req</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">then</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">success</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">fail</span> <span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">};</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">setTimeout</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">check</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1000</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">dfd</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">promise</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">};</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now, we can call our new function, and use the returned promise to react to the <em>eventual outcome</em> of the sync:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">App</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Helpers</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">checkSyncStatus</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">then</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// this will run if the sync was successful,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// once the user has been reloaded</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;it worked&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span> <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="c1">// this will run if the sync failed</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;it failed&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">);</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>With a few more lines of code, we&#8217;ve made our function safer &#8211; eliminating the possibility of an out-of-control <code>setInterval</code> &#8211; and also made it vastly more useful to other pieces of the application that care about the outcome of the sync.</p>

<p>While the example above used <a href="http://api.jquery.com/deferred.promise/">jQuery&#8217;s promises implementation</a>, there are plenty of other implementations as well, including Sam Breed&#8217;s <a href="https://github.com/wookiehangover/underscore.Deferred">underscore.Deferred</a>, which mimics the behavior of jQuery&#8217;s promises without the dependency on jQuery.</p>

<p><small>* <a href="http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/websockets/basics/">Websockets</a> are a great way to eliminate polling all together, but in the case of this application, they weren&#8217;t an option.</small></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Onward]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2013/01/18/onward/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-18T10:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2013/01/18/onward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend IM&#8217;d me a link the other day to a document he and a colleague wrote
at the end of 2011, listing all the things they wanted to make happen in the
world of web development in 2012.</p>

<p>&#8220;We did almost all of it,&#8221; he said.</p>

<p>&#8220;Well shit,&#8221; I said. &#8220;I should write up something like this for 2013.&#8221;</p>

<p>&#8220;Why do you think I showed it to you?&#8221;</p>

<hr />

<p>A year ago I was working at Toura, a startup based in New York that was
developing software to make it easy to create content-centric mobile
applications. I started there as a consultant back in 2010, helping them write
a saner version of the prototype they&#8217;d developed in the months before.</p>

<p>I got the gig because apparently I spoke with their director of development,
Matt, at a meetup in Brooklyn, though I actually have no recollection of this.
By this time last year, I&#8217;d been there for more than a year, and Matt and I had
convinced the company a few months before that the technology we&#8217;d developed &#8211;
a JavaScript framework called Mulberry that ran inside of a Phonegap wrapper
&#8211; was worth open-sourcing.</p>

<p>I spent much of January and February speaking at meetups and events &#8211;
Vancouver, Boston, Austin, Charlotte &#8211; telling people why Mulberry was
something they might consider using to develop their own content-centric mobile
apps. By March, though, it was clear that Toura was headed in a direction that
was different from where I wanted to go. As it turned out, Matt and I gave our
notice on the same day.</p>

<hr />

<p>April was the first time in almost 10 years that I purposefully didn&#8217;t work for
a solid month. I spent almost two weeks in Europe, first in Berlin and then in
Warsaw for <a href="http://2013.front-trends.com/">Front Trends</a>. I sold my car &#8211; it
mostly just sat in the driveway anyway &#8211; to make Melissa feel a bit better
about the part where I wasn&#8217;t making any money.
<a href="http://twitter.com/theophani">Tiffany</a> was a marvelous host; we took the train
together from Berlin to Warsaw for the conference, barely talking the whole way
as we worked on our respective presentations. Warsaw was a two-day whirlwind of
wonderful people &#8211; Melanie, Milos, Chris, Alex, Frances &#8211; memorable for my
terrible laryngitis and capped by endless hours of post-conference celebration
in the hotel lobby, which was magically spotless when we made our way,
bleary-eyed, to the train station early the next morning.</p>

<p>I flew home two days later; two days after that, I started at
<a href="http://bocoup.com/">Bocoup</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p>Taking a job at Bocoup was a strategic change of pace for me. For 18 months, I
had been immersed in a single product and a single codebase, and I was the
architect of it and the expert on it. As fun as that was, I was ready to
broaden my horizons and face a steady stream of new challenges in the company
of some extremely bright people.</p>

<p>As it turned out, I ended up focusing a lot more on the training and education
side of things at Bocoup &#8211; I spent the summer developing an updated and more
interactive version of <a href="http://jqfundamentals.com">jQuery Fundamentals</a>, and
worked through the summer and fall on developing and teaching various
JavaScript trainings, including a really fun two-day course on writing testable
JavaScript. I also worked on creating a
<a href="http://training.bocoup.com/coaching/">coaching</a> offering, kicked off a
<a href="http://training.bocoup.com/screencasts/">screencasts</a> project, and had some
great conversations as part of <a href="https://plus.google.com/101066175187812737186/posts">Bocoup on Air</a>.
Throughout it all, I kept up a steady schedule of speaking &#8211; TXJS, the jQuery Conference,
Fronteers, Full Frontal, and more.</p>

<p>Though I was keeping busy and creating lots of new content, there was one thing
I wasn&#8217;t doing nearly enough of: writing code.</p>

<hr />

<p>I went to New York in November to speak at the New York Times <a href="http://opensourcesciencefair.com/">Open Source Science Fair</a>,
and the next day I dropped in on Matt, my old boss from Toura, before heading
to the airport. He&#8217;s working at another startup these days, and they&#8217;re using
<a href="http://emberjs.com/">Ember</a> for their front-end.  Though I was lucky enough to
get a guided tour of Ember from Tom Dale over the summer, I&#8217;d always felt like
I wouldn&#8217;t really appreciate it until I saw it in use on a sufficiently complex
project.</p>

<p>As it turned out, Matt was looking for some JavaScript help; I wasn&#8217;t really
looking for extra work, but I figured it would be a good chance to dig in to a
real Ember project. I told him I&#8217;d work for cheap if he&#8217;d tolerate me working
on nights and weekends. He gave me a feature to work on and access to the repo.</p>

<p>The first few hours with Ember were brutal. The next few hours were manageable.
The hours after that were magical. The most exciting part of all, despite all
the brain hurting along the way, was that I was solving problems with code
again. It felt good.</p>

<hr />

<p>With much love to my friends and colleagues at Bocoup, I&#8217;ve realized it is time
to move on. I&#8217;ll be taking a few weeks off before starting as a senior
software engineer at <a href="http://www.bazaarvoice.com/">Bazaarvoice</a>, the company
behind the ratings and reviews on the websites of companies such as WalMart,
Lowe&#8217;s, Costco, Best Buy, and lots more.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re in the JS world, Bazaarvoice might sound familiar because <a href="http://alexsexton.com/">Alex Sexton</a>,
of yayQuery, TXJS, and redhead fame, works there. I&#8217;ll be joining the team he
works on, helping to flesh out, document, test, and implement a JavaScript
framework he&#8217;s been prototyping for the last several months.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve gotten tiny peeks at the framework as Alex and the rest of the team have
been working on it, starting way back in February of last year, when I flew out
to Austin, signed an NDA, and spoke at BVJS, an internal conference the company
organized to encourage appreciation for JS as a first-class citizen. Talking to
Alex and his colleagues over the last few weeks about the work that&#8217;s ahead of
them, and how I might be able to help, has quite literally given me goosebumps
more than once. I can&#8217;t wait.</p>

<hr />

<p>I look back on 2012 with a lot of mixed emotions. I traveled to the UK,
to Amsterdam, to Warsaw, to Berlin two times. I broke a bone in a foreign
country, achievement unlocked. I learned about hardware and made my first
significant code contribution to an open-source project in the process. I met
amazing people who inspired me and humbled me, and even made a few new friends.</p>

<p>What I lost sight of, though, was making sure that I was seeking out new
challenges and facing them head on, making sure that I was seeking
opportunities to learn new things, even when they were hard, even when I didn&#8217;t
have to. I didn&#8217;t realize til my work with Ember just how thoroughly I&#8217;d let
that slip, and how very much I need it in order to stay sane.</p>

<p>And so while my friend probably has his list of things he will change in the
world of web development in 2013, and while maybe I&#8217;ll get around to making
that list for myself too, the list I want to be sure to look back on, 12 months
or so from now, is more personal, and contains one item:</p>

<p><em>Do work that requires learning new things all the time. Even if that&#8217;s a
little scary sometimes. Especially if that&#8217;s a little scary sometimes. In the
end you will be glad.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Things about Conditionals in JavaScript]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/12/10/js-conditionals/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-10T21:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/12/10/js-conditionals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick post, inspired by <a href="http://laurakalbag.com/display-none/">Laura Kalbag&#8217;s post</a>, which included this gem:</p>

<blockquote><p>We shouldnt be fearful of writing about what we know. Even if you write from the most basic point of view, about something which has been around for ages, youll likely be saying something new to someone.</p></blockquote>

<h2>One: There is no <code>else if</code></h2>

<p>When you write something like this &#8230;</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">saySomething</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">msg</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">msg</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Hello&#39;</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Hello there&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">msg</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Yo&#39;</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Yo dawg&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>&#8230; then what you&#8217;re actually writing is this &#8230;</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">saySomething</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">msg</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">msg</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Hello&#39;</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Hello there&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">msg</span> <span class="o">===</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Yo&#39;</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">console</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;Yo dawg&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>That&#8217;s because there is no <code>else if</code> in JavaScript. You know how you can write an <code>if</code> statement without any curly braces?</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">foo</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="nx">bar</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="c1">// please don&#39;t do this if you want your code to be legible</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You&#8217;re doing the same thing with the <code>else</code> part of the initial <code>if</code> statement when you write <code>else if</code>: you&#8217;re skipping the curly braces for the second <code>if</code> block, the one you&#8217;re providing to <code>else</code>. There&#8217;s nothing <em>wrong</em> with <code>else if</code> per se, but it&#8217;s worth knowing about what&#8217;s actually happening.</p>

<h2>Two: <code>return</code> Means Never Having to Say <code>else</code></h2>

<p>Consider some code like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">howBig</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">10</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;small&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">10</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">100</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;medium&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">100</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;big&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>If the number we pass to <code>howBig</code> is less than 10, then our function will return <code>'small'</code>. As soon as it returns, none of the rest of the function will run &#8211; this means we can skip the <code>else</code> part entirely, which means our code could look like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">howBig</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">10</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;small&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">100</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;medium&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">100</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;big&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>But wait &#8211; if the first <code>if</code> statement isn&#8217;t true, and the second <code>if</code> statement isn&#8217;t true, then we will <em>always</em> return <code>'big'</code>. That means the third <code>if</code> statement isn&#8217;t even required:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">howBig</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">10</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;small&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">num</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">100</span> <span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;medium&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s1">&#39;big&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><small><em>Note: this post was edited to improve a couple of the examples and to fix some typos.</em></small></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is the Cigarette]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/12/09/this-is-the-cigarette/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-09T19:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/12/09/this-is-the-cigarette</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rdmey/8259827572/" title="Untitled by rdmey, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8212/8259827572_73b5a4e269.jpg" width="200"></a></p>

<p>This is the cigarette I smoked* on Wednesday after I got out of a meeting in Boston and went to my desk and read my messages and learned that our birthmother &#8220;match&#8221; had fallen through.</p>

<p>The last three weeks have been among the happiest, most exciting, most terrifying times I can remember. Saying that we are sad and disappointed and et cetera doesn&#8217;t really cover it, but, well, there it is. Our search will continue.</p>

<p><small>* Don&#8217;t worry, Mom, I don&#8217;t usually smoke. Desperate times, desperate measures.</small></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Choosing a Syntax Highlighting Scheme for Your Next Presentation]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/29/choosing-presentation-color-scheme/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-29T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/29/choosing-presentation-color-scheme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a projector screen:</p>

<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2916642/projection-screen.jpg" width="300px"></p>

<p>You will notice that it is white, or some reasonable approximation thereof. It is probably made of a reflective material that sparkles a bit when light shines on it. Still: white.</p>

<p>Do you know what color this screen is when you use a projector to display this image onto it?</p>

<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/2916642/dark-code.png" width="300px"></p>

<p>It is still white. Crazy, I know! The thing is, projectors cannot project black; they can only <em>not</em> project any light on a region that you intend to be black.</p>

<p>Chances are you are reading this on an LCD screen of some sort, where the rules are completely different: they usually start out essentially black, not white, and pixels are brightened as required. The pixels that start out dark can generally stay pretty dark.</p>

<p>On a projection screen, on the other hand, the appearance of black is nothing more than an optical illusion, made possible by the projector projecting brightness everywhere else.</p>

<p>What does this mean? Lots of things, but in particular, it means that you should never, ever, ever use a color scheme with a dark background &#8211; no matter how high-contrast and good it looks on your monitor &#8211; if you will be presenting using a projector that is projecting onto a white screen. At least, assuming that you intend for your audience to be able to actually read the code.</p>

<h3>Presentation Color Schemes That I Have Loved</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://gist.github.com/4171437">Ben Alman&#8217;s TextMate Theme</a>: Ben has tailored this to be incredible for presenting about JS code.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/chriskempson/tomorrow-theme">Tomorrow Theme</a>: The light-background flavor is decent, but could probably stand to be higher-contrast, at least for some languages.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show & Tell]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/25/times-open-science-fair/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/25/times-open-science-fair</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spoke at the <a href="http://opensourcesciencefair.com/">Times Open Source Science Fair</a> a couple of weeks ago. I&#8217;ll admit that I was pretty skeptical of the concept when I was first asked, but as someone who used to work as an editor at a tiny newspaper in upstate New York, I wasn&#8217;t about to say no when the Times asked me to come say hi.</p>

<p>A few days before the event, I got an email asking me for information about what I&#8217;d be showing off at my booth. Booth? Wat? They weren&#8217;t kidding about the science fair thing, but what the heck was I going to show at a booth?</p>

<p>It turns out this is basically the best idea ever. I recruited my Bocoup colleague <a href="http://twitter.com/rwaldron">Rick Waldron</a> to join me, and together we spent a whirlwind hour showing off <a href="https://github.com/rwldrn/johnny-five">robots powered by JavaScript</a> to an endless stream of people walking up to our booth. Rick did a great job of setting up a demo that people could play with, and they took turns moving <a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/9119">sliding potentiometers</a> that controlled <a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/9064">servos</a> that moved an arm with a gripper at the end, trying to pick up Bocoup stickers. Ours was one of about a <a href="http://open.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/11/21/open-source-science-fair-exhibitor-experiences/">dozen booths</a> showing off open-source projects, and the room was a wonderful madhouse.</p>

<p>After a break for dinner, I, <a href="http://twitter.com/jashkenas">Jeremy Ashkenas</a>, and <a href="http://twitter.com/holman">Zach Holman</a> each gave 20-minute talks, but the talks were really just icing on the evening. The &#8220;science fair&#8221; format promoted such <em>intentional interaction</em>, in a way that traditional conferences just can&#8217;t, no matter how great the hall track or the parties may be. The format invited and encouraged attendees to talk to the presenters &#8211; indeed, if they didn&#8217;t talk to the presenters, there wasn&#8217;t much else for them to do. By the time the official talks came around, a super-casual, super-conversational atmosphere had already been established, and the energy that created was tangibly different from any event I&#8217;ve been to before.</p>

<p>I love conferences, and the sharing of knowledge that happens there, and there&#8217;s a whole lot to be said for their speaker-audience format &#8211; don&#8217;t get me wrong. But I&#8217;d also love to see more events figure out how to integrate this show and tell format. &#8220;Booths&#8221; don&#8217;t need to mean &#8220;vendors trying to sell things&#8221; &#8211; they can actually be a great opportunity to facilitate conversation, and to let open source contributors show off their hard work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recent Talks]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/21/recent-talks/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T10:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/21/recent-talks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://infrequently.org/2012/11/bits-and-remainders/">A post from Alex Russell</a> reminded me that I&#8217;ve given a number of talks in the last few months, and some of them even have video on the internet.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been ridiculously spoiled to get to travel all over the place these last few months &#8211; San Francisco, New York, Amsterdam, Berlin, Brighton &#8211; and speak at some truly first-class conferences, sharing the stage, sharing meals, and sharing beers with some seriously amazing folks. My <a href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/14/this-is-the-cup-of-coffee/">recent news</a> means I&#8217;ll be doing a lot less travel for the next little bit, but I&#8217;m ever-so-grateful for the opportunities I&#8217;ve had and the people I&#8217;ve gotten to see and meet these last few months.</p>

<h3>Writing Testable JavaScript</h3>

<p>This is the first talk I&#8217;ve developed that I&#8217;ve managed to give several times in rapid succession: three times in six days, including at <a href="http://2012.full-frontal.org/">Full Frontal</a>, the online <a href="http://environmentsforhumans.com/2012/javascript-summit/">JS Summit</a>, and to a group of developers at the New York Times. There&#8217;s no video yet, but the <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/rmurphey/writing-testable-javascript-mocha-version">slides are here</a>, and there should be video soon, I think.</p>

<p><script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="eb8bb4800ff201308f97123138155402" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="http://rmurphey.com//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script></p>


<h3>JS Minty Fresh</h3>

<p>A fun talk at <a href="http://fronteers.nl/congres/2012">Fronteers</a> about eliminating code smells from your JavaScript. The best feedback I got afterwards was from an attendee who said they felt at the beginning of the talk like the material was going to be too basic for them, and by the end of the talk, the material was nearly over their head. &#8220;I guess that makes you a good teacher,&#8221; he said. Aw!</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/53416986?badge=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>




<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/53416986">Rebecca Murphey | JS Minty Fresh: Identifying and Eliminating Smells in Your Code Base | Fronteers 2012</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/fronteers">Fronteers</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>


<p><a href="http://rmurphey.com/js-minty-fresh/presentation/">Slides</a></p>

<p>If you like this, you should also check out the <a href="http://training.bocoup.com/screencasts/">screencasts</a> we released at Bocoup earlier this week.</p>

<h3>Beyond the DOM: Sane Structure for JS Apps</h3>

<p>An update of my code organization talk, delivered at the <a href="http://events.jquery.org/2012/sf/">jQuery Conference in San Francisco</a>. It&#8217;s fun for me to see how my thinking around code organization has evolved and improved since my first, now-almost-embarassing talk at the 2009 jQuery Conference in Boston.</p>

<iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/cd7HHN6IkrU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/rmurphey/jquery-conference-sf-2012-beyond-the-dom-sane-structure-for-js-apps">Slides</a></p>

<h3>Johnny Five: Bringing the JavaScript Culture to Hardware</h3>

<p>This one was from the New York Times <a href="http://opensourcesciencefair.com/">Open Source Science Fair</a>, a fun night of about a dozen folks presenting open-source projects at &#8220;booths,&#8221; followed by short talks about open source by Jeremy Ashkenas, me, and Zach Holman. The slides don&#8217;t necessarily stand on their own very well, but the short version is: use JavaScript to make things in the real world, because it&#8217;s ridiculously easy and ridiculously fun.</p>

<p><script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="6ab92f30161e0130f5111231381d612b" data-ratio="1.2994923857868" src="http://rmurphey.com//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script></p>


<h3>Getting Better at JavaScript</h3>

<p>I put this together as a quickie for the Berlin <a href="http://up.front.ug/">UpFront</a> user group &#8211; it was the first talk I gave with my broken foot, and the last talk I&#8217;d give for weeks because I lost my voice a couple of hours later. There&#8217;s not a whole lot here, but it was a fun talk and a fun group, and a topic that I get plenty of questions about. Again, no video, but here are the slides:</p>

<p><script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="50746953453e4d0002081c02" data-ratio="1.2994923857868" src="http://rmurphey.com//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is the Cup of Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/14/this-is-the-cup-of-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T10:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/11/14/this-is-the-cup-of-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8482/8187360514_db246b4ac9.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>This is the cup of coffee I was making earlier this week when Melissa gave me a thumbs-up while she talked on the phone to a woman in Pennsylvania who had just finished telling Melissa that yes, indeed, after 10 weeks or three years of waiting depending on how you count, a 29-year-old woman who&#8217;s due to give birth in Iowa at the beginning of February has decided that Melissa and I should be so lucky as to get to be her baby girl&#8217;s forever family.</p>

<p>Most people get to post ultrasound pictures on Twitter at moments like these, but for now this will suffice to remind me of the moment I found out I would get to be a mom. My head is spinning, and while on the one hand it&#8217;s a little difficult to fathom that this is all just 10 weeks away, on the other hand I&#8217;m counting down the days.</p>

<p>Our adoption will be an open one; the meaning of &#8220;open&#8221; varies widely, but in our case it means we talked to the birth mother before she chose us, we&#8217;ll be meeting her in a few weeks, we&#8217;ll do our very best to be in Iowa for the delivery, and we&#8217;ll stay in touch with letters and pictures afterwards. Melissa and I are grateful that we&#8217;ll be able to adopt as a couple, though we are saddened that we have to adopt outside of our home state of North Carolina in order to do so. It&#8217;s important to us that our child have both of us as her <em>legal</em> parents, and I don&#8217;t hesitate to say that it&#8217;s downright shitty that we have to jump through significant legal and financial hoops &#8211; and stay in a hotel in Iowa with a newborn for an unknown number of days &#8211; to make it so. It is what it is, and good people are working and voting to make it better, and it can&#8217;t happen fast enough.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve learned a lot about adoption these past few months, and I know a lot of people have a lot of questions, some of which they&#8217;re reluctant to ask. If you&#8217;re interested in learning more, I <em>highly</em> recommend <a href="http://www.amazon.com/In-On-It-Adoption-Relatives/dp/0982876505/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1352948795&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=in+on+it">In On It: What Adoptive Parents Would Like You to Know About Adoption</a>. You&#8217;re also welcome to ask me questions if you see me in real life or on the internets &#8211; I can&#8217;t promise I&#8217;ll know the answers, but I promise to do my best.</p>

<p>In the meantime, wish us luck :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Baseline for Front-End Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/12/a-baseline-for-front-end-developers/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-12T11:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/12/a-baseline-for-front-end-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a README the other day for a project that I&#8217;m hoping other developers will look at and learn from, and as I was writing it, I realized that it was the sort of thing that might have intimidated the hell out of me a couple of years ago, what with its casual mentions of Node, npm, Homebrew, git, tests, and development and production builds.</p>

<p>Once upon a time, editing files, testing them locally (as best as we could, anyway), and then FTPing them to the server was the essential workflow of a front-end dev. We measured our mettle based on our ability to wrangle IE6 into submission or achieve pixel perfection across browsers. Many members of the community &#8211; myself included &#8211; lacked traditional programming experience. HTML, CSS, and JavaScript &#8211; usually in the form of jQuery &#8211; were self-taught skills.</p>

<p>Something has changed in the last couple of years. Maybe it&#8217;s the result of people starting to take front-end dev seriously, maybe it&#8217;s browser vendors mostly getting their shit together, or maybe it&#8217;s front-end devs &#8211; again, myself included &#8211; coming to see some well-established light about the process of software development.</p>

<p>Whatever it is, I think we&#8217;re seeing the emphasis shift from valuing trivia to valuing tools. There&#8217;s a new set of baseline skills required in order to be successful as a front-end developer, and developers who don&#8217;t meet this baseline are going to start feeling more and more left behind as those who are sharing their knowledge start to assume that certain things go without saying.</p>

<p>Here are a few things that <em>I</em> want to start expecting people to be familiar with, along with some resources you can use if you feel like you need to get up to speed. (Thanks to Paul Irish, Mike Taylor, Angus Croll, and Vlad Filippov for their contributions.)</p>

<h2>JavaScript</h2>

<p>This might go without saying, but simply knowing a JavaScript library isn&#8217;t sufficient any more. I&#8217;m not saying you need to know how to implement all the features of a library in plain JavaScript, but you should know when a library is actually required, and be capable of working with plain old JavaScript when it&#8217;s not.</p>

<p>That means that you&#8217;ve read <a href="http://www.amazon.com/JavaScript-Good-Parts-Douglas-Crockford/dp/0596517742">JavaScript: The Good Parts</a> &#8211; hopefully more than once. You understand data structures like objects and arrays; functions, including how and why you would <code>call</code> and <code>apply</code> them; working with prototypal inheritance; and managing the asynchronicity of it all.</p>

<p>If your plain JS fu is weak, here are some resources to help you out:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net">Eloquent Javascript</a>: A wonderful book (also available in print) that takes you back to JavaScript basics</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/js-assessment">A Test-Driven JS Assessment</a>: A set of failing tests that cover various JavaScript topics; can you write code to make the tests pass?</li>
<li><a href="http://paulirish.com/2010/10-things-i-learned-from-the-jquery-source/">10 things I learned from the jQuery Source</a> is an oldie but goodie from Paul Irish that shows what you can learn by reading other people&#8217;s code.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Git (and a Github account)</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;re not on Github, you&#8217;re essentially unable to participate in the rich open-source community that has arisen around front-end development technologies. Cloning a repo to try it out should be second-nature to you, and you should understand how to <a href="http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/">use branches on collaborative projects</a>.</p>

<p>Need to boost your git skills?</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://help.github.com/">help.github.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://help.github.com/git-cheat-sheets/">Github git cheat sheet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://cheat.errtheblog.com/s/git">More cheat sheet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pinboard.in/u:rmurphey/t:git/">More git links</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Modularity, dependency management, and production builds</h2>

<p>The days of managing dependencies by throwing one more script or style tag on the page are long gone. Even if you haven&#8217;t been able to incorporate great tools like <a href="http://requirejs.org">RequireJS</a> into your workflow at work, you should find time to investigate them in a personal project or in a project like <a href="https://github.com/tbranyen/backbone-boilerplate">Backbone Boilerplate</a>, because the benefits they convey are huge. RequireJS in particular lets you develop with small, modular JS and CSS files, and then concatenates and minifies them via its optimization tool for production use.</p>

<p>Skeptical of AMD? That&#8217;s no excuse to be doing nothing. At the very least, you should be aware of tools like <a href="https://github.com/mishoo/UglifyJS">UglifyJS</a> or <a href="https://developers.google.com/closure/compiler/">Closure Compiler</a> that will intelligently minify your code, and then concatenate those minified files prior to production.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re writing plain CSS &#8211; that is, if you&#8217;re not using a preprocessor like Sass or Stylus &#8211; RequireJS can help you keep your CSS files modular, too. Use <code>@import</code> statements in a base file to load dependencies for development, and then run the RequireJS <a href="http://requirejs.org/docs/optimization.html#onecss">optimizer</a> on the base file to create a file built for production.</p>

<h2>In-Browser Developer Tools</h2>

<p>Browser-based development tools have improved tremendously over the last couple of years, and they can dramatically improve your development experience if you know how to use them. (Hint: if you&#8217;re still using <code>alert</code> to debug your code, you&#8217;re wasting a lot of time.)</p>

<p>You should probably find one browser whose developer tools you primarily use &#8211; I&#8217;m partial to <a href="https://developers.google.com/chrome-developer-tools/">Google Chrome&#8217;s Developer Tools</a> these days &#8211; but don&#8217;t dismiss the tools in other browsers out of hand, because they are constantly adding useful features based on developer feedback. Opera&#8217;s <a href="http://my.opera.com/dragonfly/blog/">Dragonfly</a> in particular has some features that make its developer tools stand out, such as an (experimental) CSS profiler, customizable keyboard shortcuts, remote debugging without requiring a USB connection, and the ability to save and use custom color palettes.</p>

<p>If your understanding of browser dev tools is limited, <a href="http://fixingthesejquery.com/#slide1">Fixing these jQuery</a> is a great (and not particularly jQuery-centric) overview of debugging, including how to do <a href="https://developers.google.com/chrome-developer-tools/docs/scripts-breakpoints">step debugging</a> &#8211; a life-altering thing to learn if you don&#8217;t already know it.</p>

<h2>The command line</h2>

<p>Speaking of the command line, being comfortable with it is no longer optional &#8211; you&#8217;re missing out on way too much if you&#8217;re not ready to head over to a terminal window and get your hands dirty. I&#8217;m not saying you have to do <em>everything</em> in the terminal &#8211; I won&#8217;t take your git GUI away from you even though I think you&#8217;ll be better off without it eventually &#8211; but you should absolutely have a terminal window open for whatever project you&#8217;re working on. There are a few command line tasks you should be able to do without thinking:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>ssh</code> to log in to another machine or server</li>
<li><code>scp</code> to copy files to another machine or server</li>
<li><code>ack</code> or <code>grep</code> to find files in a project that contain a string or pattern</li>
<li><code>find</code> to locate files whose names match a given pattern</li>
<li><code>git</code> to do at least basic things like <code>add</code>, <code>commit</code>, <code>status</code>, and <code>pull</code></li>
<li><code>brew</code> to use Homebrew to install packages</li>
<li><code>npm</code> to install Node packages</li>
<li><code>gem</code> to install Ruby packages</li>
</ul>


<p>If there are commands you use frequently, edit your <code>.bashrc</code> or <code>.profile</code> or <code>.zshrc</code> or whatever, and create an <a href="http://tldp.org/LDP/abs/html/aliases.html">alias</a> so you don&#8217;t have to type as much. You can also add aliases to your <code>~/.gitconfig</code> file. Gianni Chiappetta&#8217;s <a href="https://github.com/gf3/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> are an excellent inspiration for what&#8217;s possible.</p>

<p><em>Note: If you&#8217;re on Windows, I don&#8217;t begin to know how to help you, aside from suggesting <a href="http://www.cygwin.com/">Cygwin</a>. Right or wrong, participating in the open-source front-end developer community is materially more difficult on a Windows machine. On the bright side, MacBook Airs are cheap, powerful,  and ridiculously portable, and there&#8217;s always Ubuntu or another *nix.</em></p>

<h2>Client-side templating</h2>

<p>It wasn&#8217;t so long ago that it was entirely typical for servers to respond to XHRs with a snippet of HTML, but sometime in the last 12 to 18 months, the front-end dev community saw the light and started demanding pure data from the server instead. Turning that data into HTML ready to be inserted in the DOM can be a messy and unmaintainable process if it&#8217;s done directly in your code. That&#8217;s where <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/garann/using-templates-to-achieve-awesomer-architecture">client-side templating libraries</a> come in: they let you maintain templates that, when mixed with some data, turn into a string of HTML. Need help picking a templating tool? Garann Means&#8217; <a href="http://garann.github.com/template-chooser/">template chooser</a> can point you in the right direction.</p>

<h2>CSS preprocessors</h2>

<p>Paul Irish <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/paul_irish/status/188329390822801409">noted</a> the other day that we&#8217;re starting to see front-end devs write code that&#8217;s very different from what ends up in production, and code written with CSS preprocessors is a shining example of this. There&#8217;s still a vocal crowd that feels that pure CSS is the only way to go, but they&#8217;re <a href="http://www.stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/less">starting to come around</a>. These tools give you features that arguably should be in CSS proper by now &#8211; variables, math, logic, mixins &#8211; and they can also help smooth over the CSS property prefix mess.</p>

<h2>Testing</h2>

<p>One of the joys of writing modular, loosely coupled code is that your code becomes vastly easier to test, and with tools like <a href="https://github.com/cowboy/grunt">Grunt</a>, setting up a project to include tests has never been easier. Grunt comes with QUnit integration, but there are a host of testing frameworks that you can choose from &#8211; <a href="https://github.com/pivotal/jasmine/wiki">Jasmine</a> and <a href="http://visionmedia.github.com/mocha/">Mocha</a> are a couple of my current favorites &#8211; depending on your preferred style and the makeup of the rest of your stack.</p>

<p>While testing is a joy when your code is modular and loosely coupled, testing code that&#8217;s not well organized can be somewhere between difficult and impossible. On the other hand, forcing yourself to write tests &#8211; perhaps before you even write the code &#8211; will help you organize your thinking <em>and</em> your code. It will also let you refactor your code with greater confidence down the line.</p>

<ul>
<li>A short <a href="http://vimeo.com/20457625">screencast</a> I recorded about testing your jQuery with Jasmine.</li>
<li>An example of <a href="https://github.com/cowboy/jquery-bbq/blob/master/unit/unit.js">unit tests</a> on the jquery-bbq plugin.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Process automation (rake/make/grunt/etc.)</h2>

<p>Grunt&#8217;s ability to set up a project with built-in support for unit tests is one example of process automation. The reality of front-end development is that there&#8217;s a whole lot of repetitive stuff we have to do, but as a friend once told me, a good developer is a lazy developer: as a rule of thumb, if you find yourself doing the same thing three times, it&#8217;s time to automate it.</p>

<p>Tools like <code>make</code> have been around for a long time to help us with this, but there&#8217;s also <code>rake</code>, <code>grunt</code>, and others. Learning a language other than JavaScript can be extremely helpful if you want to automate tasks that deal with the filesystem, as Node&#8217;s async nature can become a real burden when you&#8217;re just manipulating files. There are lots of task-specific automation tools, too &#8211; tools for deployment, build generation, code quality assurance, and more.</p>

<h2>Code quality</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;ve ever been bitten by a missing semicolon or an extra comma, you know how much time can be lost to subtle flaws in your code. That&#8217;s why you&#8217;re running your code through a tool like <a href="http://www.jshint.com/">JSHint</a>, right? It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.jshint.com/options/">configurable</a> and has lots of ways to integrate it into your <a href="http://www.jshint.com/platforms/">editor or build process</a>.</p>

<h2>The fine manual</h2>

<p>Alas, there is no manual for front-end development, but <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/">MDN</a> comes pretty close. Good front-end devs know to prefix any search engine query with <code>mdn</code> &#8211; for example, <code>mdn javascript arrays</code> &#8211; in order to avoid the for-profit plague that is w3schools.</p>

<h2>The End</h2>

<p>As with anything, reading about these things won&#8217;t make you an expert, or even moderately skilled &#8211; the only surefire way to get better at a thing is to <a href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2011/05/20/getting-better-at-javascript/">do that thing</a>. Good luck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greenfielding]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/10/greenfielding/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T12:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/10/greenfielding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m officially one-third of the way through my self-imposed month of unemployment before I join <a href="http://bocoup.com">Bocoup</a> at the beginning of May, and I&#8217;ve been spending most of what would normally be my working hours on a small demo to support talks at <a href="http://2012.front-trends.com/">conferences</a> I will be <a href="http://backboneconf.com/">speaking at</a> this <a href="http://2012.texasjavascript.com/">summer</a>. It&#8217;s just a <a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/srchr-demo">little app</a> that searches various services, and displays the results &#8211; so simple that, when I showed it to Melissa, she helpfully asked why I wouldn&#8217;t just use Google.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s been about 18 months since I last got to start a project from scratch &#8211; in that case, the codebase that became <a href="http://mulberry.toura.com">Mulberry</a> &#8211; but even then, I didn&#8217;t have control over the full stack of technologies, just the JavaScript side of things. Over the course of my time on that project, I came to be extremely familiar with Dojo, fairly competent with Jasmine, decently comfortable with Ruby and its go-to simple server Sinatra, and somewhat conversational in Sass.</p>

<p>I spent most of my time on that project working with technologies with which I was already pretty comfortable. Interactions with new technologies came in dribs and drabs (except for that one time I decided to test my Ruby skills by rewriting our entire build process), and all of my learning was backed up by a whole lot of institutional knowledge.</p>

<p>The consulting world, of course, is a wee bit different: you interact frequently with new technologies, and you never know what a client might ask you to do. Learning comes in bursts, and the ability to quickly come up to speed with a technology is imperative. On a six-week project, you can&#8217;t spend the first 40 hours getting your bearings.</p>

<p>Even though I spent three years as a consultant, returning to that world of constant learning was feeling a tad intimidating. And so for this project, I decided to make a point of leaving that comfort zone, and intentionally chose technologies &#8211; Node, Bootstrap, Backbone, Mocha, RequireJS &#8211; that I hadn&#8217;t really had a chance to work with in depth (or at all).</p>

<h2>On Learning</h2>

<p>Greenfield projects are few and far between, and it&#8217;s easy to get in a rut by sticking with the tools you already know. Some of my most exciting times at Toura weren&#8217;t when I was writing JavaScript, but rather when I was learning how to talk to the computer in a whole new language. Greenfielding a personal project is a special treat &#8211; it never really has to be &#8220;finished,&#8221; and no one&#8217;s going to be mad at you if it turns out you made a shitty choice, so you&#8217;re free to try things that are less of a sure thing than they would need to be if you were getting paid.</p>

<p>Speaking personally, it can also be a little intimidating to learn a new thing because learning often involves asking for help, and asking for help requires admitting that I don&#8217;t already know how to do the thing that people might expect I already know how to do.</p>

<p>Sometimes the thing that gets in the way of starting a new learning project is actually the fear that I will get stuck. What does it mean if the person who talks at conferences about principles code organization can&#8217;t figure out how best to structure a particular app with Backbone? What does it mean if the person who&#8217;s been encouraging people to build their JavaScript can&#8217;t get RequireJS to generate a proper build? What will I say to <a href="http://blog.izs.me/">Isaac</a>, now that he is standing in front of me and introducing himself, when I have not in fact spent any quality time with Node prior to this past weekend?</p>

<p>Lucky for me, it turns out that all of this is mostly in my head. While I often preface my questions with a small dose of humility and embarrassment, it turns out that well articulated questions are usually greeted with thoughtful and helpful answers. If anything, I&#8217;m trying to be more communicative about the learning that I do, because I think it&#8217;s important that people feel comfortable acknowledging that they used to not know a certain thing, and now they do. I also try to gently remind people that just because they have known something for months or years doesn&#8217;t mean they should look down upon the person enthusiastically blogging about it today.</p>

<p>On that note &#8230; here&#8217;s what&#8217;s new to me these past couple of weeks :)</p>

<h2>Twitter Bootstrap</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve written a lot of demo apps, and while my coding style has changed over the years, one thing has remained constant: they all look fairly terrible. In theory, we&#8217;re all smart enough to know that what a demo looks like doesn&#8217;t have any bearing on what it explains, but in reality a good-looking demo is simply more compelling, if only because the viewer isn&#8217;t distracted by the bad design.</p>

<p>With this in mind, I decided to give <a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/">Twitter Bootstrap</a> a try. When I first arrived at the site, I started looking for docs about how to set it up, but it turns out that I vastly overestimated Bootstrap&#8217;s complexity. Drop a style tag into your page (and, optionally, another style tag for the responsive CSS), look at the <a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/examples.html">examples</a>, and start writing your markup.</p>

<p>What I really loved is that there were patterns for everything I needed, and those patterns were easy to follow and implement. Within an hour or so I had a respectable-looking HTML page with markup that didn&#8217;t seem to suck &#8211; that is, it looked good <em>and</em> it was a decent starting point if I ever wanted to apply a custom design.</p>

<h2>Node</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;ve ever talked to me about Node, you know that I have pretty mixed feelings about it &#8211; some days I feel like the people writing JavaScript in the browser really would have benefited if the people who have gravitated to Node had stuck around to invest their collective smarts in the world where 99% of JavaScript is still written. But that doesn&#8217;t really have anything to do with Node the technology, so much as Node the new shiny thing unburdened by browser differences.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve actually visited Node a couple of times previously &#8211; if you haven&#8217;t at least installed it, you might be living under a rock &#8211; and I was flattered that <a href="http://dev.garann.com">Garann</a> asked me to review her book <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920023258.do">Node for Front-End Developers</a>, but past experiences had left me frustrated.</p>

<p>This time, something was different. I don&#8217;t rule out that it might be me, or even that learning some of the ins and outs of Ruby might have prepared me to understand Node &#8211; and packages and dependency management and writing for the server instead of the browser &#8211; better this time around. It could also be that the Node ecosystem has reached a point of maturity that it just hadn&#8217;t reached the last time I poked around.</p>

<p>Regardless, I found that everything made a whole lot more sense this time, and my struggles this time were about forgetting to stringify an object before sending it as a response to a request, not about getting the server to start in the first place. I used the <code>q</code> module to give me my beloved promises for managing all the asynchronicity, and generally found it ridiculously pleasant to leave behind all the context switching I&#8217;d grown accustomed to while using JavaScript and Ruby side by side. I&#8217;ll probably still turn to Ruby for automating things on the command line (though I continue to be intrigued by <a href="https://github.com/cowboy/grunt">grunt</a>), but I&#8217;m ready to admit that it&#8217;s time for me to add Node to my toolbox.</p>

<h2>Mocha</h2>

<p>To be honest, I&#8217;d just planned on using <a href="https://github.com/pivotal/jasmine">Jasmine</a> for writing tests for this project, mostly because I&#8217;d never set up Jasmine myself, and I was interested in maybe getting it working with grunt for headless testing. I ended up bailing on that plan when, in the course of some Googling for answers about Jasmine, I came across <a href="http://visionmedia.github.com/mocha/">Mocha</a>.</p>

<p>Mocha is a super-flexible testing framework that runs on Node and in the browser. You can choose your assertion library &#8211; that is, you can choose to write your tests like <code>assert(1, 1).ok()</code> or <code>expect(1).to.be(1)</code> depending on your preference. I decided to use the latter style, with the help of <a href="https://github.com/LearnBoost/expect.js">expect.js</a>. You can also choose your reporting style, including the ability to generate docs from your tests.</p>

<p>I had to do a bit of finagling to get the browser-based tests working with my
RequireJS setup, and ultimately I ended up just using my app&#8217;s server, running
in dev mode, to serve the tests in the browser. I&#8217;m still working out how best
to run just one test at a time in the browser, but all in all, discovering Mocha has probably been the best part of working on this project.</p>

<h2>RequireJS</h2>

<p><a href="http://requirejs.org/">RequireJS</a> is another tool that I&#8217;ve dabbled with in the past, but for the last 18 months I&#8217;ve been spending most of my time with Dojo&#8217;s pre-AMD build system, so I had some catching up to do. I don&#8217;t have a ton to say about RequireJS except:</p>

<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s gotten even easier to use since I last visited it.</li>
<li>The docs are great and also gorgeous.</li>
<li>While I haven&#8217;t had to bother him lately, James Burke, the author and maintainer of RequireJS, is a kind and incredibly helpful soul.</li>
<li>The <a href="http://requirejs.org/docs/api.html#text"><code>text!</code></a> plugin makes working with client-side templates incredibly simple, without cluttering up your HTML with templates in script tags or hard-coding your templates into your JavaScript.</li>
<li>The <a href="https://github.com/tbranyen/use.js"><code>use!</code></a> plugin makes it painless to treat libraries that don&#8217;t include AMD support just like libraries that do. I hear it might become an official plugin soon; I hope it will.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Backbone</h2>

<p>This part was a tough choice, and I actually set out to use a different framework but ended up getting cold feet &#8211; even though this was just a personal project, it did need to reach some semblance of done-ness in some reasonable period of time. After a little bit of poking around at other options, I decided that, barring completely copping out and using Dojo, Backbone was going to be the best tool for this particular job on this particular schedule.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m pretty torn about this, because I decided to use a framework that I <em>know</em> has shortcomings and limited magic, and I <em>know</em> that other options would serve me better in the long term. But I also know that the long term doesn&#8217;t exactly matter for this particular project. The thing that swayed me, really, was that with Backbone, I didn&#8217;t feel like I needed to grasp a whole slew of concepts before I could write my first line of code.</p>

<p>I looked up plenty of things along the way, and rewrote my fair share of code when I discovered that I&#8217;d been Doing It Wrong, but I was able to maintain a constant forward momentum. With the other options I considered, I felt like I was going to have to climb a ladder of unknown height before making any forward progress.</p>

<p>I feel like I made the right choice for this project, but it&#8217;s a choice I&#8217;d spend a lot more time on for a &#8220;real&#8221; project, and I&#8217;d be much more inclined to invest the initial energy in getting up to speed if the payoff was clearer. This, though, is a choice that people seem to be consistently terrible at, and so I feel like I should beat myself up about it just a little. It&#8217;s all too common to dig a ginormous hole for ourselves by choosing the technology that lets us start writing code the soonest; on the flip side, it&#8217;s all too common to choose a technology that&#8217;s complete overkill for the task at hand.</p>

<h2>The End</h2>

<p>The master branch of the <a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/srchr-demo">repo for the project</a> should be mostly stable (if incomplete) if you want to check it out. I&#8217;m going to close comments on this post in the hopes that you&#8217;ll write your own post about what you&#8217;ve been learning instead :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript: It's a language, not a religion]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/04/javascript-a-language-not-a-religion/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T11:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/04/04/javascript-a-language-not-a-religion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have six things to say:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>I am in a committed relationship with my partner Melissa. We will celebrate
six years together on Sunday. We contribute frequently to political causes.</p></li>
<li><p>I was deeply saddened yesterday to learn that Brendan Eich contributed money
in support of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_Proposition_8">political initiative</a> that
sought to <em>rescind the court-established right for same-sex couples to
marry</em> in the state of California. It has changed my view of him as a
person, despite the fact that we have had a positive and professional
relationship and he has been a great supporter of my JavaScript career. I
think he is on the wrong side of history, and I hope that courts will
continue to agree with me.</p></li>
<li><p>I had a frank, private, and face-to-face conversation with Brendan about the
issue during JSConf. I shared my disappointment, sadness, and disagreement.</p></li>
<li><p>I have been dismayed to see this incident interpreted as a statement about
the JavaScript community as a whole. This community is made up of so many
people who believe so many different things, and yesterday I was reminded
that they are all just people, and JavaScript is just a language, not a
religion.  I shudder to think of a world where there is a political litmus
test for entry into the community.  Indeed, I am extremely torn about
introducing personal politics into my professional life*, as I fear it will
encourage professional colleagues to opine about personal beliefs that are
frankly none of their business. One of the great joys of working with
computers is that they <a href="http://raganwald.posterous.com/a-womans-story">do not care who I am or what I believe</a>;
I realize that to ask the same of people is unreasonable, but inviting
politics into the workplace is a treacherously slippery slope. Unless my
personal belief system presents an <em>imminent danger</em> to my colleagues, I am
loath to welcome discussion of it by people who otherwise have no
substantial or personal relationship with me.</p></li>
<li><p>I believe individual companies must determine how best to address these
issues, as their attitude toward them can have a significant impact on their
ability to hire and retain talented people. I support <em>constructive
pressure</em> on companies to align themselves with or distance themselves from
political causes, but I would not support a company that prohibited its
employees from participating in the political process. I urge anyone who is
hurt or offended by this incident to engage with Brendan and Mozilla
personally and professionally. Brendan is wrong on this issue, but he is a
thoughtful and intelligent person, and he is also a human being.</p></li>
<li><p>Finally: If this incident has made you angry or sad or disappointed, the most effective
thing you can do is follow in Brendan&#8217;s footsteps by <strong>putting your money
where your mouth is</strong>. Money speaks volumes in the American political
system, and there are campaigns in progress right now that will <a href="http://www.protectncfamilies.org/">impact the rights of gays and lesbians</a>.
Your <a href="https://protectallncfamilies.ngpvanhost.com/crmapi/contribute">contribution</a>
of $50, $100, or $1,000 &#8211; or, in lieu of money, your time &#8211; will have far
more impact than yet another angry tweet.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>And now I shall turn off the internet for a bit. Comments are disabled.
Shocker, I know.</p>

<p>* <em>It bears mentioning that, in certain cases, people making political
contributions are required to include information about their employer. The
inclusion of this information does not indicate that the employer supports &#8211;
or is even aware of &#8211; the contribution.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bocoup]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/26/bocoup/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/26/bocoup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://rmurphey.com/images/bocoup.png" alt="bocoup" /></p>

<p>It wasn&#8217;t so long ago that I was giving my first talk about JavaScript at the
2009 jQuery Conference, and it was there that Bocoup&#8217;s Boaz Sender and Rick
Waldron created the (now-defunct) objectlateral.com, a celebration of an
unfortunate typo in the conference program&#8217;s listing of my talk.</p>

<p>A bond was forged, and ever since I&#8217;ve watched as <a href="http://bocoup.com">Bocoup</a>
has grown and prospered. I&#8217;ve watched them do mind-boggling work for the likes
of Mozilla, The Guardian, Google, and others, all while staying true to their
mission of embracing, contributing to, and evangelizing open-web technologies.</p>

<p>Today, I&#8217;m beyond excited &#8211; and also a wee bit humbled &#8211; to announce that
<a href="http://weblog.bocoup.com/welcome-rebecca-murphey">I&#8217;m joining their consulting team</a>.
As part of that role, I look forward to spending even more time working on and
talking about patterns and best practices for developing client-side JavaScript
applications. I also hope to work on new <a href="http://training.bocoup.com/">training offerings</a>
aimed at helping people make great client-side applications with web technology.</p>

<p>New beginnings have a terrible tendency to be accompanied by endings, and while
the Bocoup opportunity is one I couldn&#8217;t refuse, it&#8217;s with a heavy heart that I
bid farewell to the team at Toura. I&#8217;m proud of what we&#8217;ve built together, and
that we&#8217;ve shared so much of it with the developer community in the form of
<a href="http://github.com/Toura/mulberry">Mulberry</a>. The beauty of open source means
that I fully expect to continue working on and with Mulberry once I leave
Toura, but I know it won&#8217;t be the same.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be spending the next few days tying up loose ends at Toura, and then I&#8217;m
taking a break in April to hit JSConf, spend some time in Berlin, and head to
Warsaw to speak at <a href="http://2012.front-trends.com/">FrontTrends</a>. I&#8217;ll make my
way back home in time to start with Bocoup on May 1.</p>

<p>And so. To my teammates at Toura: I wish you nothing but the best, and look
forward to hearing news of your continued success. To Bocoup: Thanks for
welcoming me to the family. It&#8217;s been a long time coming, and I&#8217;m glad the day
is finally here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Girls and Computers]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/25/girls-and-computers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/25/girls-and-computers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a week that seemed just chock full of
<a href="http://storify.com/ireneros/sexist-language-earns-sqoot-lots-of-fury">people</a>
being <a href="http://storify.com/charlesarthur/oh-hai-sexism">stupid</a> about women in
technology, I just found myself thinking back on how it was that I ended up
doing this whole computer thing in the first place.  I recorded a video a while
back for the <a href="http://highvisibilityproject.org/2011/10/rebecca-murphey/">High Visibility Project</a>, but that
really just told the story of how I ended up doing web development. The story
of how I got into computers begain when I was unequivocally a girl. It was
1982.</p>

<p>Back then, my dad made eyeglasses. My mom stayed at home with me and my
year-old sister &#8211; which she&#8217;d continue to do til I was a teenager, when my
brother finally entered kindergarten eight years later. Their mortgage was $79
&#8211; about $190 in today&#8217;s dollars &#8211; which is a good thing because my dad made
about $13,000 a year. We lived in Weedsport, New York, a small town just
outside of Syracuse. We walked to the post office to get our mail. The farmers
who lived just outside town were the rich people. In the winters the fire
department filled a small depression behind the elementary school with water
for a tiny skating rink. There were dish-to-pass suppers in the gym at church.</p>

<p>In 1982, Timex came out with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timex_Sinclair">Timex Sinclair TS-1000</a>,
selling 500,000 of them in just six months. The computer, a few times thicker
than the original iPad but with about the same footprint, cost $99.95 &#8211; more
than that mortgage payment. When everyone else in town was getting cable,
my parents decided that three channels were good enough for them &#8211; it&#8217;s
possible they still had a black-and-white TV &#8211; and bought a computer instead.</p>

<p><img src="http://rmurphey.com/images/ts1000.JPG" alt="Timex Sinclair TS-1000" /></p>

<p>I remember tiny snippets of that time &#8211; playing kickball in my best friend
Beth&#8217;s yard, getting in trouble for tricking my mother into giving us milk that
we used to make mud pies, throwing sand in the face of my friend Nathan
because I didn&#8217;t yet appreciate that it really sucks to get sand thrown in your
face &#8211; but I vividly remember sitting in the living room of our house on
Horton Street with my father, playing with the computer.</p>

<p>A cassette player was our disk drive, and we had to set the volume just right
in order to read anything off a tape &#8211; there was actually some semblance of a
flight simulator program that we&#8217;d play, after listening to the tape player
screech for minutes on end. Eventually we upgraded the computer with a
fist-sized brick of RAM that we plugged into the back of the computer, bumping
our total capacity from 2K to 34K. I wrote programs in BASIC, though for the
life of me I can&#8217;t remember what any of them did. The programs that were the
most fun, though, were the ones whose assembly I painstakingly transcribed,
with my five-year-old fingers, from the back of magazines &#8211; pages and pages of
letters and numbers I didn&#8217;t understand on any level, and yet they made magic
happen if I got every single one right.</p>

<p>A string of computers followed. My parents bought a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coleco_Adam">Coleco Adam</a> when we moved
to Horseheads, New York &#8211; apparently the computer came with a certificate
redeemable for $500 upon my graduation from high school, but Coleco folded long
before they could cash it in. I made my first real money by typing a crazy
lady&#8217;s crazy manuscript about crazy food into an Apple IIe that we had plugged
into our TV, and my uncle and I spent almost the entirety of his visit from
Oklahoma writing a game of Yahtzee! on that computer, again in BASIC.</p>

<p><img src="http://rmurphey.com/images/rebecca-computer.jpg" alt="Me at a computer fair at the mall with my sister, my mother, and my friend
Michael" /></p>

<p><em>Above: Me at a computer fair at the mall with my sister, my
mother, and my friend Michael. &#8220;You were giving us all a tutorial, I can tell,&#8221;
says my mom. Note the 5-1/4&#8221; external floppy drive.</em></p>

<p>In middle school, I started a school newspaper, and I think we used some
prehistoric version of PageMaker to lay it out. When high school rolled around,
I toiled through hand-crafting the perfect letters and lines and arrows in
Technical Drawing so I could take CAD and CAM classes and make the computer
draw letters and lines and arrows for me, and quickly proceeded to school just
about every boy in the class. In my senior year of high school, I oversaw the
school yearbook&#8217;s transition from laying out pages on paper to laying out pages
with computers, this time the vaguely portable (it had a handle on the back!)
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macintosh_Classic">Mac Classic</a>.
We used PageMaker again; the screen was black and white and 9&#8221;, diagonally.</p>

<p><img src="http://rmurphey.com/images/mac-classic.jpg" alt="Macintosh Classic" /></p>

<p>It was around then that a friend gave me a modem and &#8211; to his eventual
chagrin, when he got the bill &#8211; access to his Delphi account, giving me my
first taste of the whole Internet thing in the form of telnet, gopher, and IRC.
When I went to college the following year, I took with me a computer with
perhaps a 10MB hard drive, and no mouse.</p>

<p>Once again I found myself poring over magazines to discover URIs and,
eventually, URLs that I could type to discover a whole new world of
information. In 1995, I spent the summer making my college newspaper&#8217;s web
site, previewing it in Lynx &#8211; it felt like there wasn&#8217;t much to learn when
there was so little difference between the markup and what I saw on the screen.
I would go to the computer lab to use NCSA&#8217;s Mosaic on the powerful RISC 6000
workstations, because they had a mouse. Yahoo! was about one year old. My
friend Dave, who lived down the street, installed Windows 95 that summer and
invited me over to show me. It was amazing. We were living in the future.</p>

<p>My early years with computers seem pretty tame &#8211; I wasn&#8217;t tearing them apart
or building my own or doing anything particularly interesting with them, but I
was using them, I was telling them what to do and they were mostly listening,
and <em>it never made me feel like I was weird</em>. To the contrary, it made me
feel powerful and empowered. I felt like a part of this ever-growing community
of people who understood, eventually, that computers were going to change the
world. It was the people who didn&#8217;t understand this who were weird and beneath
us. It was the people who understood computers better than me of whom I stood in
awe.</p>

<p>I can barely remember a time when computers weren&#8217;t a part of my life, and yet
when they first entered my life, their presence was incredibly exceptional.
These days, of course, computers are ubiquitous, but interaction with them at
the copy-assembly-from-the-back-of-a-magazine level is almost nonexistent.
Parents who can approach a computer with the same awe and wonder and
determination as a child &#8211; as I must imagine that my dad did in 1982 &#8211; are
likely equally rare.</p>

<p>In some ways, it is like the very ubiquity of technology has led us back to a
world where socially normative gender roles take hold all over again, and the
effort we&#8217;re going to need to put into overcoming that feels overwhelming
sometimes. Words can&#8217;t express my gratitude for the parents I have, for
that $99.95 investment they made in me, and for fact that I was lucky enough to
be 5 and full of wonder in 1982.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on a (very) small project with Backbone and Backbone Boilerplate]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/11/thoughts-on-a-very-small-project-with-backbone-and-backbone-boilerplate/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T21:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/11/thoughts-on-a-very-small-project-with-backbone-and-backbone-boilerplate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I worked with <a href="http://documentcloud.github.com/backbone/">Backbone</a> and the
<a href="https://github.com/tbranyen/backbone-boilerplate">Backbone Boilerplate</a> for
the first time last weekend, putting together a small <a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/bvjs">demo app</a> for a presentation I gave last week at
BazaarVoice. I realize I&#8217;m about 18 months late to the Backbone party, here,
but I wanted to write down my thoughts, mostly because I&#8217;m pretty sure they&#8217;ll
change as I get a chance to work with both tools more.</p>

<h2>Backbone</h2>

<p>Backbone describes itself as a tool that &#8220;gives structure to web applications,&#8221;
but, at the risk of sounding pedantic, I think it would be more accurate to say
that it gives you tools that can help you structure your applications. There&#8217;s
incredibly little prescription about how to use the tools that Backbone
provides, and I have a feeling that the code I wrote to build my simple app
looks a lot different than what someone else might come up with.</p>

<p>This lack of prescription feels good and bad &#8211; good, because I was able to use
Backbone to pretty quickly set up an infrastructure that mirrored ones I&#8217;ve
built in the past; bad, because it leaves open the possibility of lots of
people inventing lots of wheels. To its credit, it packs a lot of power in a
very small package &#8211; 5.3k in production &#8211; but a real app is going to require
layering a lot more functionality on top of it. Ultimately, the best way to
think of Backbone is as the client-side app boilerplate you&#8217;d otherwise have to
write yourself.</p>

<p>My biggest complaint about Backbone is probably how unopinionated it is about
the view layer. Its focus seems to be entirely on the data layer, but the view
is still where we spend the vast majority of our time. Specifically, I think
Backbone could take a page from Dojo, and embrace the concept of &#8220;templated
widgets&#8221;, because that&#8217;s what people seem to be doing with Backbone views
anyway: mixing data with a template to create a DOM fragment, placing that
fragment on the page, listening for user interaction with the fragment, and
updating it as required. Backbone provides for some of this, specifically the
event stuff, but it leaves you to write your own functionality when it comes to
templating, placing, and updating. I think this is a solveable problem without
a whole lot of code, and want to spend some time trying to prove it, but I know
I need to look into the Backbone Layout Manager before I get too carried away.</p>

<h2>Backbone Boilerplate</h2>

<p>This project from Tim Branyen was a life-saver &#8211; it gave me an absolutely
enormous head start when it came to incorporating
<a href="http://requirejs.org/">RequireJS</a>, setting up my application directories, and
setting up a development server. It also included some great inline docs that
helped me get my bearings with Backbone.</p>

<p>There are a couple of ways I think the boilerplate could be improved, and I&#8217;d be
curious for others&#8217; opinions:</p>

<ul>
<li>The sample app includes the concept of &#8220;modules,&#8221; which seem to be a single
file that include the models, collections, views, and routes for a &#8230;
module. I don&#8217;t love the idea of combining all of this into a single file,
because it seems to discourage smart reuse and unit testing of each piece of
functionality. In the app I created, I abandoned the concept of modules, and
instead broke my app into &#8220;components&#8221;, &#8220;controllers&#8221;, and &#8220;services&#8221;. I
explain this breakdown in a bit more depth in the <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/rmurphey/bvjs">presentation I gave at BazaarVoice</a>. I&#8217;m not sure this is
the right answer for all apps, but I think modules oversimplify things.</li>
<li>The boilerplate includes a <code>namespace.js</code> file. It defines a namespace
object, and that object includes a <code>fetchTemplate</code> method. It seems this
method should only be used by views, and so I&#8217;d rather see something along
the lines of an enhanced View that provides this functionality. That&#8217;s what I
did with the <a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/bvjs/blob/master/app/components/base.js">base component module</a>
in my sample app.</li>
<li>I&#8217;m super-glad to see Jasmine included in the test directory, but
unfortunately the examples show how to write Jasmine tests, not Jasmine tests
for a Backbone app. As a community, we definitely need to be showing more
examples of how to test things, and this seems like a good opportunity to
distribute that knowledge.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Overall</h2>

<p>I feel a little silly that I&#8217;m just now getting around to spending any time
with Backbone, and I know that I only scratched the surface, but I like what I
saw. I think it&#8217;s important to take it for what it is: an uber-tiny library
that gets you pointed in the right direction. What I really want to see are
fuller-fledged frameworks that build on top of Backbone, because I think
there&#8217;s a lot more that can be standardized beyond what Backbone offers. I&#8217;m
hoping to have a bit more time in April to dig in, and hopefully I can flesh
out some of these ideas into something useful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Community Conferences]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/08/community-conferences/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T08:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/08/community-conferences</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2010, I helped put on the first TXJS. We sold our first tickets for $29, and
I think the most expensive tickets went for something like $129. We had about
200 people buy tickets, we had speakers like Douglas Crockford, Paul Irish, and
John Resig, and we had sponsors like Facebook and Google. Our total budget was
something like $30,000, and every out-of-town speaker had their travel and
accommodations paid for.</p>

<p>In May, O&#8217;Reilly Media is holding another JavaScript conference in San
Francisco, called FluentConf. I recently came to know that they are charging
$100,000 for top-tier sponsorships, and that they are offering a 10-minute
keynote as part of the package.</p>

<p>This turned my stomach, and not just because I believe it cheapens the
experience of attendees, who will pay hundreds of dollars themselves. What
really upset me was that a few weeks ago, I was approached to be on the speaker
selection committee of FluentConf, and that conversation led me to discover
that FluentConf would not be paying for speaker travel and accommodations. And
so the other day, I tweeted:</p>

<blockquote><p>conference #protip: save your money &#8211; and your speaking skills &#8211; for events that don&#8217;t sell their keynotes for $100k</p></blockquote>

<p>Last night, I was at the Ginger Man in Austin, and I checked the Twitters,
discovering that Peter Cooper, one of the chairs of FluentConf, had replied to
a conversation that arose from that tweet:</p>

<blockquote><p>@rmurphey @tomdale If you&#8217;re referring to Fluent, that is news to me.</p></blockquote>

<p>I will accept the weird fact that the co-chair of a conference didn&#8217;t know its
speaking slots were for sale &#8211; I gather that it is essentially a volunteer
role, and the co-chairs aren&#8217;t necessarily in the driver&#8217;s seat when it comes
to decisions like this. I let Peter know that, indeed, I had a PDF that
outlined all the sponsorship options.</p>

<p>This is the part where, in some alternate reality, a mutual understanding of
the offensiveness of this fact would have been achieved. What happened instead
was a whole lot of name-calling, misquoting, and general weirdness.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the deal. Conferences can run their event however they want, and they
can make money hand over fist. They can even claim they are the giving
JavaScript developers &#8220;an event of their own,&#8221; ignoring the existence of
the actual community-run JavaScript events that have been around for years now.  I
probably won&#8217;t go to or speak at an event that makes money hand over fist, but
I don&#8217;t have any problem with the existence of such events, or with people&#8217;s
involvement with them.  However, when a conference is making money hand over
fist &#8211; my back of the napkin calculations would suggest that FluentConf stands
to have revenues of well over a million dollars &#8211; then that conference has no
excuse not to pay the relatively paltry costs associated with speaker travel
and accommodations.</p>

<p>A conference does not exist without its speakers. Those who speak at an event
&#8211; the good ones, anyway &#8211; spend countless hours preparing and rehearsing, and
they are away from home and work for days. While I do not discount the benefits
that accrue to good speakers, the costs of being a speaker are non-trivial &#8211;
and that&#8217;s <em>before</em> you get into the dollar costs of travel and accommodations.</p>

<p>When an event is unwilling to cover even those hard costs &#8211; nevermind the
preparation time and time away from work and home &#8211; it materially affects the
selection of speakers.  It&#8217;s even worse when those same conferences claim to
desire <a href="http://fluentconf.com/fluent2012/public/content/about#diversity">diversity</a>;
the people they claim to want so badly are the very people most likely to be
discouraged when they find out they have to pay their own way to the stage.</p>

<p>In the conversation last night, I made this point:</p>

<blockquote><p>when only the people who can afford to speak can speak, then only the people who can afford to speak will
speak.</p></blockquote>

<p>Amy Hoy responded with a criticism of community-run conferences:</p>

<blockquote><p>and when only ppl who can order a ticket in 3 seconds can afford to come, only ppl who can order a ticket in 3 seconds can come</p></blockquote>

<p>I know that getting tickets to the actual community-run events is hard, but
that is because the community-run events flat-out ignore the economics of
supply and demand, choosing instead to sell tickets at affordable prices even
if it means they will sell out in a heartbeat, leaving a boatload of potential
profit on the table. And yet those events &#8211; JSConf, TXJS, and the like &#8211; have
still figured out how to cover speaker costs and provide attendees and sponsors
with unforgettable experiences.</p>

<p>When an event with revenues exceeding a million dollars is unwilling to cover
those costs, while simultaneously selling speaking slots, I do not hesitate for
a moment to call that event out, and I do not hesitate to call
on <a href="http://fluentconf.com/fluent2012/public/content/about#commitee">respected members of the community</a> to sever
their ties with the event. I&#8217;m not embarrassed about it, and you can call me all
the names you want.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
