<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts, | Adventures in JavaScript Development]]></title>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/categories/thoughts-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-10T22:33:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rmurphey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Murphey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 reasons you don't really want a jack-of-all-trades developer]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2008/08/02/5-reasons-you-don-t-really-want-a-jack-of-all-trades-developer/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2008/08/02/5-reasons-you-don-t-really-want-a-jack-of-all-trades-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've spent the last couple of weeks trolling Craigslist and have been shocked at the number of ads I've found that seem to be looking for an entire engineering team rolled up into a single person. Descriptions like this aren't at all uncommon:</p>


<blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote">Candidates must have 5 years experience defining and developing data driven web sites and have solid experience with ASP.NET, HTML, XML, JavaScript, CSS, Flash, SQL, and optimizing graphics for web use. The candidate must also have project management skills and be able to balance multiple, dynamic, and sometimes conflicting priorities. This position is an integral part of executing our web strategy and must have excellent interpersonal and communication skills.</blockquote>


<p>Really.  Now I don't know about you, but if I were building a house, I wouldn't want an architect doing the work of a carpenter, or the foundation guy doing the work of an electrician. But ads like the one above are suggesting that a single person can actually do all of these things, and the simple fact is that these are <em>fundamentally different skills</em>. The foundation guy may build a solid base, but put him in charge of wiring the house and the whole thing could, well, burn down. When it comes to staffing a web project or product, the principle isn't all that different -- nor is the consequence.  I've thought a lot about this these last couple of weeks, and I don't think this post is sour grapes about the fact that I don't have the top-to-bottom, front-to-back web development skills that this ad and others seem to be asking for. I'm proud and confident of the abilities I've assembled when it comes to front-end development, and I have a rock-solid understanding of what makes websites tick.  The thing is, the more you know, the more you find out you don't know. A year ago I'd have told you I could write PHP/MySQL applications, and do the front-end too; now that I've seen what it means to be truly skilled at the back-end side of things, I realize the most accurate thing I can say is that I understand PHP applications and how they relate to my front-end development efforts. To say that I can write them myself is to diminish the good work that truly skilled PHP/MySQL developers are doing, just as I get a little bent when a back-end developer thinks they can do my job.  So to all of those companies who are writing ads seeking one magical person to fill all of their needs, I offer a few caveats before you post your next Craigslist ad:</p>


<ol>
<li>If you're seeking a single person with all of these skills, make sure you have the technical expertise to determine whether a person's skills match their resume. Outsource a tech interview if you need to. Any developer can tell horror stories about inept predecessors, but when a front-end developer like myself can read PHP and think it's appalling, that tells me someone didn't do a very good job of vetting and got stuck with a programmer who couldn't deliver on his stated skills.</li>
<li>A single source for all of these skills is a single point of failure on multiple fronts. Think long and hard about what it will mean to your project if the person you hire falls short in some aspect(s), and about the mistakes that will have to be cleaned up when you get around to hiring specialized people. I have spent countless days cleaning up after back-end developers who didn't understand the nuances and power of CSS, or the difference between a div, a paragraph, a list item, and a span. Really.</li>
<li>Writing efficient SQL is different from efficiently producing web-optimized graphics. Administering a server is different from troubleshooting cross-browser issues. Trust me. All are integral to the performance and growth of your site, and so you're right to want them all -- just not from the same person. Expecting quality results in every area from the same person goes back to the foundation guy doing the wiring. You're playing with fire.</li>
<li>Asking for a laundry list of skills may end up deterring the candidates who will be best able to fill your actual need. Be precise in your ad: about the position's title and description, about the level of skill you're expecting in the various areas, about what's nice to have and what's imperative. If you're looking to fill more than one position, write more than one ad; if you don't know exactly what you want, try harder to figure it out before you click the publish button.</li>
<li>If you really do think you want one person to do the task of an entire engineering team, prepare yourself to get someone who is OK at a bunch of things and not particularly good at any of them. Again: the more you know, the more you find out you don't know. I regularly team with a talented back-end developer who knows better than to try to do my job, and I know better than to try to do his. Anyone who represents themselves as being a master of front-to-back web development may very well have no idea just how much they don't know, and could end up imperiling your product or project -- front to back -- as a result.</li>
</ol>


<p>If your budget really is limited to a single position, you might want to consider whether you'd be better off working with several contractors with specific and proven skills, rather than a single person who claims to encompass everything you're after. Your management overhead will increase in the short term, yes, but your headaches down the road will decrease exponentially. In the process, you'll gain access to people who can help you evaluate potential full-timers, and probably gain some insight into the actual list of skills a full-timer needs to provide.  If you're one of the people who's written these ads, all is not lost. Invest in a technical consultant -- probably one you can't afford to hire full-time -- to help you really understand your needs and the skills required to solve them. Often they can assist you with writing and posting the ad, and interviews too. For example, I'll meet with a client, write and post a detailed ad, identify candidates, and interview contenders; if I don't have the technical skills required to evaluate a candidate, chances are I personally know someone who can. Doing that homework up front, and understanding and describing what your needs <em>really</em> are, is vastly more likely to give you the perfect fit you're after than if you just cast a wide net and see what you catch.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I learned CSS]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/24/how-i-learned-css/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/24/how-i-learned-css</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember when I first tried to understand how to produce designs for the web -- coming from the paper-based world, it was hard for me to accept everything that was suddenly out of my control. When I first tried to grasp CSS with the help of now-defunct Adobe GoLive, I bailed pretty quickly. Table-based layout and font tags didn't make much sense to me either -- why did I have to slice up a page into a bunch of adjoining cells, instead of just drawing independent boxes like I did in Quark?</p>

<p>A couple of years later, I decided to try again, motivated by the realization that my <a href="http://gmurphey.com/">eight-years-younger brother</a> seemed to be better at this web stuff than I was. I spent untold hours trying to wrap my brain around <a href="http://www.sustainablewebdesign.com/resources/601/">the difference between margin and padding</a> and exactly how to <a href="http://css.maxdesign.com.au/floatutorial/">get floated elements to bend to my will</a>. I remember the epiphany that one could <a href="http://www.sovavsiti.cz/css/horizontal_menu.html">use left-floated list items for a horizontal menu</a>, or that <a href="http://www.netmechanic.com/news/vol4/html_no22.htm">the right DOCTYPE can force Internet explorer to behave more like a real browser</a>.</p>

<p>These days, I have an honest-to-god job doing this stuff, and every now and then, someone will ask me how they can learn it too. It all makes so much more sense to me than it used to that it's hard to remember how I got here. In the interest of getting this stuff written down for passing along, though, here are a few thoughts:</p>

<h3>The Tools</h3>


<p>These are things without which the rest is impossible:</p>

<ul>
<li>
<strong>A text editor</strong> Notepad will do just fine; for a few bucks, you can get <a href="http://macromates.com/">TextMate</a> for Mac or the <a href="http://www.e-texteditor.com/">e Text Editor</a> for PC. If you use Dreamweaver, hide everything but the file navigator panel and the code editing view. <em>You will learn nothing from Dreamweaver's "design" view.</em>
</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/">Firefox</a></strong> You'll need to test anything you do in Internet Explorer, but first, you'll get it working in Firefox. Whereas Internet Explorer enjoys mocking web standards, Firefox does its best to adhere to them; plus, it has all sorts of extensions that make it easier to troubleshoot your work.</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/60">Firefox Web Developer Toolbar</a></strong> This has all sorts of useful tools in it, including a real-time CSS editor that opens in the browser's sidebar so you try changes to your CSS and see the results immediately.</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1843">Firebug</a></strong> This is most useful for Javascript debugging, but it has some nice features for debugging CSS as well.</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="http://users.skynet.be/mgueury/mozilla/">HTML Validator</a></strong> Incredibly helpful for finding errors in your HTML.</li>
</ul>


<p>(An aside: A few months ago I booted up an old laptop and found a preview release of Firefox 1.0 installed beside a well-worn Internet Explorer 6; when I abandoned the laptop, I was in the process of abandoning IE too. I can't help but wonder how difficult my learning would have continued to be without the arrival of Firefox, which, with the extensions mentioned above, makes it so much more possible to learn all of this stuff in a very tangible, immediate sort of way.)</p>

<h3>Learning with Firefox</h3>


<p>Once you have the tools above, open Firefox and start with a page someone else built -- like the one you're on right now -- and see what's inside. It pays to be curious about every web page you visit; if you see something interesting, view the source and figure out how it got there. Some tips:</p>

<ul>
<li>
<code>Ctrl-U</code> will show you the HTML for a page, and with the HTML Validator extension, you can "clean up" the HTML so it's easier to read.</li>
<li>
<code>Ctrl-Shift-E</code> will open the Web Developer Toolbar CSS editor, which will show you the CSS for the page, with a tab for each CSS file. You can edit the CSS in the editor and see the effects immediately.</li>
<li>
<code>F12</code> will open Firebug. In the top left of the panel that opens, click the Inspect menu item, then move your mouse back to the page itself and click on an element to find out more about it. You can also click on the HTML tab to view the HTML and expand and collapse sections of it to see the structure of the page. Hovering over an element in the HTML panel will highlight it on the page; clicking on an element will let you find out more about it in the Style and Layout tabs of Firebug. (Firebug is an incredibly powerful tool that you really need to play with to fully appreciate. It's a completely non-destructive tool -- you can't hurt anything with it unless you try really, really hard -- so don't be afraid to click around and see what happens.)</li>
<li>Remember that these days, lots of page elements are built with Javascript rather than with straight HTML. <code>Ctrl-U</code> will show you only the HTML; Firebug will show you the "generated source," including any elements built with Javascript. Firebug also lets you look at the Javascript on a page, which can be helpful when you're trying to understand how something got there.
</li>
</ul>




<h3>POSH</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.456bereastreet.com/archive/200711/posh_plain_old_semantic_html/">Plain-old semantic HTML</a>. When you go to make a web page, write the simplest HTML you can, and use standard HTML elements whenever humanly possible. Start by creating HTML that represents the actual sections of the page -- header, navigation, sidebar, content, footer -- and give the elements names that say what they <em>are</em>, not where they go. When you think you're done, view the HTML in a browser, without CSS, and see if it makes sense. Then, <em>and only then</em>, open the browser's CSS editor and start styling the elements. See how far you can get without adding any design-related markup to your HTML. If you find yourself writing convoluted HTML or adding purely presentational markup, to make something work, it's time to reconsider your approach. Once you have a good stylesheet started, copy it to your text editor and continue working on it there.</p>

<h3>Strategies</h3>


<p>It helps to give yourself deadlines, even if they're imaginary. I've learned more about HTML, CSS and Javascript in the past 12 months than I learned in the three years before, and I think that's largely because deadlines have forced me to solve problems rather than pondering them.</p>

<p>Don't be afraid to do something less than perfectly; there can be value in just getting it done. I constantly look back at things I did three months ago -- let alone three years ago, and sometimes three weeks ago -- and I cringe when I think how differently I would do them today. But half the reason I know what I know now is precisely because I <em>didn't</em> know it then, and I learned it along the way. Understanding the building blocks of the web is an iterative process, and you'll do better if you remember that <strong>you cannot know everything you wish you knew</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
