<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: css, | Adventures in JavaScript Development]]></title>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/categories/css-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-20T14:13:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rmurphey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Murphey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS vs. Tables: Maybe the design is to blame?]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2009/02/14/css-vs-tables-maybe-the-design-is-to-blame/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2009/02/14/css-vs-tables-maybe-the-design-is-to-blame</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There's been some backlash lately against CSS, and some of it seems so well reasoned that even I find myself wondering if tables are really so bad after all. From <a href="http://giveupandusetables.com/">giveupandusetables.com</a>, which says the maximum time to spend before abandoning CSS is 47 minutes, to the <a href="http://www.flownet.com/ron/css-rant.html">well-illustrated blog post by Ron Garret</a>, the general argument is that CSS isn't up to the task of faithfully reproducing elaborate designs cross-browser in an acceptable amount of developer time.</p>

<p>In his post about Garret's article, <a href="http://ajaxian.com/archives/css-for-layout-another-rant">Dion Almaer at Ajaxian</a> opines:</p>

<blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote">CSS purist[s] may poo poo him and say "he is just dumb and doesn't REALLY know CSS." The problem though is that most developers run into exactly the pain that he describes. We’ve all been there. It drives you nuts and when frustrated what do you do? You fluster about and change CSS like a mad man until it kinda looks right. And, you never learn what the real problem was, and thus destined to make the same mistake again.</blockquote>


<p>It seems that while developers are thinking about sacrificing web standards for the perceived simplicity of tables, the viability of the design rarely enters the debate, and that's a shame. In my experience, some of the most difficult designs to produce using CSS were fundamentally flawed from the get-go, created by designers who failed to grasp that the web is not like print.</p>

<p><strong>The web is not like print.</strong> In print, designers have near-total control over the output, because the number of new "pages" -- items of content -- is limited by the cost of printing. If a print designer wants text vertically centered in a fixed-height column, or two columns that are exactly the same height, or rounded corners with drop shadows on top of gradients, there's no reason they can't have that. The cost of printing is sufficiently high, and print graphics programs are sufficiently sophisticated, that making those design decisions has no impact on the marginal cost of production.</p>

<p>On the web, the marginal cost of creating a new page of content can be approximately zero, but to achieve that we <em>must</em> build pages that adapt to unpredictable content and unpredictable users. If we don't, we won't realize the economies of scale that the web has to offer. The tradeoff for that infinitesimally small marginal cost is that the rules have to be different, because the cost of implementing those print-centric design decisions is inordinately high. Instead of sophisticated graphics programs, the web has mere humans to turn PSDs into working pages; instead of content created by experts and pored over by editors, the web has volumes of user-generated content, and the ability to change it on a whim.</p>

<p>On the web, equal-height columns will cease to be equal height when the content changes; vertically centered content will outgrow its fixed-height bounds; and rounded corners with drop shadows on gradients can't possibly be worth the cost of producing them. These are not problems with CSS that should be solved with tables. They are, fundamentally, problems with the design.</p>

<p>When I talk about this to other developers (and any designers who are willing to give me the time of day after I'm done pointing out how costly their design will be to produce), I make the analogy that it's just as absurd to impose these print-centric design conventions on the web as it would be to use holograms for every picture in a magazine. Sure, you <em>can</em>, but that doesn't mean you <em>should</em>.</p>

<p><strong>So what's a web developer to do?</strong> When designs reach the desk of the CSS developer, more often than not they've been through so many rounds of review, revision, and approval -- by people far-removed from the realities of the web -- that the developer has little choice but to toil away at reproducing them faithfully.</p>

<p>The best defense may be a good offense, which is to say, the burden is on you, dear developer, to educate the misguided designers. Here are some tactics I've used:</p>

<ul>
<li>Impose yourself early in the process, insisting on wireframes and information architecture documents (even if they're just sketches and an outline). Identify potential problems early on, but don't become a naysayer -- make sure you offer ideas, not just criticism.</li>
<li>Push back -- gently but firmly -- on design decisions that have the potential to cause problems down the road. Ask lots of "what if" questions and insist on answers.</li>
<li>Be honest about how long it will take you to accomplish a design -- with yourself and with your boss or client -- and identify opportunities to make cost-saving changes to the specifics of the design without changing its spirit.</li>
<li>Have examples at the ready of similar problems solved in more web-centric ways. The <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/ypatterns/">Yahoo! Design Patterns Library</a> can be an excellent resource for this, but look also to other sites in your industry or genre.</li>
</ul>


<p>The burden's also on you to get better at CSS. I am lucky in that, when I first started playing around with web production, I was a little intimidated by tables. A background in print production steeped in templates and stylesheets made tables seem awkward and strange to me; CSS, temperamental as it was, at least bore some resemblance to the cascading style sheets of print production programs like Quark and InDesign.</p>

<p>These days, it's rarer and rarer (but not unheard of) that I find myself beating my head against the wall over a CSS problem. I've learned HTML and CSS patterns that I reuse often, and I've learned to spot -- and speak up about -- design-induced ratholes. If you're finding yourself sucked in by the latest round of CSS vs. tables debate, take heart, stand firm, and reconsider the source of your frustration.</p>

<h3>Useful things:</h3>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.rebeccamurphey.com/2007/12/24/learning-css-web-design/">How I learned CSS</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.stubbornella.org/content/2009/02/12/css-doesn%E2%80%99t-suck-you%E2%80%99re-just-doing-it-wrong/">CSS doesn't suck, you're just doing it wrong</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/stubbornella/object-oriented-css">Object-oriented CSS</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Centering images]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2008/06/13/centering-images/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2008/06/13/centering-images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.netmechanic.com/news/vol7/html_no10.htm">An excellent article explaining the pros and cons of different image-centering methods</a>. I love when I find something that gives me exactly the answer I need.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I learned CSS]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/24/how-i-learned-css/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/24/how-i-learned-css</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember when I first tried to understand how to produce designs for the web -- coming from the paper-based world, it was hard for me to accept everything that was suddenly out of my control. When I first tried to grasp CSS with the help of now-defunct Adobe GoLive, I bailed pretty quickly. Table-based layout and font tags didn't make much sense to me either -- why did I have to slice up a page into a bunch of adjoining cells, instead of just drawing independent boxes like I did in Quark?</p>

<p>A couple of years later, I decided to try again, motivated by the realization that my <a href="http://gmurphey.com/">eight-years-younger brother</a> seemed to be better at this web stuff than I was. I spent untold hours trying to wrap my brain around <a href="http://www.sustainablewebdesign.com/resources/601/">the difference between margin and padding</a> and exactly how to <a href="http://css.maxdesign.com.au/floatutorial/">get floated elements to bend to my will</a>. I remember the epiphany that one could <a href="http://www.sovavsiti.cz/css/horizontal_menu.html">use left-floated list items for a horizontal menu</a>, or that <a href="http://www.netmechanic.com/news/vol4/html_no22.htm">the right DOCTYPE can force Internet explorer to behave more like a real browser</a>.</p>

<p>These days, I have an honest-to-god job doing this stuff, and every now and then, someone will ask me how they can learn it too. It all makes so much more sense to me than it used to that it's hard to remember how I got here. In the interest of getting this stuff written down for passing along, though, here are a few thoughts:</p>

<h3>The Tools</h3>


<p>These are things without which the rest is impossible:</p>

<ul>
<li>
<strong>A text editor</strong> Notepad will do just fine; for a few bucks, you can get <a href="http://macromates.com/">TextMate</a> for Mac or the <a href="http://www.e-texteditor.com/">e Text Editor</a> for PC. If you use Dreamweaver, hide everything but the file navigator panel and the code editing view. <em>You will learn nothing from Dreamweaver's "design" view.</em>
</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/">Firefox</a></strong> You'll need to test anything you do in Internet Explorer, but first, you'll get it working in Firefox. Whereas Internet Explorer enjoys mocking web standards, Firefox does its best to adhere to them; plus, it has all sorts of extensions that make it easier to troubleshoot your work.</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/60">Firefox Web Developer Toolbar</a></strong> This has all sorts of useful tools in it, including a real-time CSS editor that opens in the browser's sidebar so you try changes to your CSS and see the results immediately.</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1843">Firebug</a></strong> This is most useful for Javascript debugging, but it has some nice features for debugging CSS as well.</li>
<li>
<strong><a href="http://users.skynet.be/mgueury/mozilla/">HTML Validator</a></strong> Incredibly helpful for finding errors in your HTML.</li>
</ul>


<p>(An aside: A few months ago I booted up an old laptop and found a preview release of Firefox 1.0 installed beside a well-worn Internet Explorer 6; when I abandoned the laptop, I was in the process of abandoning IE too. I can't help but wonder how difficult my learning would have continued to be without the arrival of Firefox, which, with the extensions mentioned above, makes it so much more possible to learn all of this stuff in a very tangible, immediate sort of way.)</p>

<h3>Learning with Firefox</h3>


<p>Once you have the tools above, open Firefox and start with a page someone else built -- like the one you're on right now -- and see what's inside. It pays to be curious about every web page you visit; if you see something interesting, view the source and figure out how it got there. Some tips:</p>

<ul>
<li>
<code>Ctrl-U</code> will show you the HTML for a page, and with the HTML Validator extension, you can "clean up" the HTML so it's easier to read.</li>
<li>
<code>Ctrl-Shift-E</code> will open the Web Developer Toolbar CSS editor, which will show you the CSS for the page, with a tab for each CSS file. You can edit the CSS in the editor and see the effects immediately.</li>
<li>
<code>F12</code> will open Firebug. In the top left of the panel that opens, click the Inspect menu item, then move your mouse back to the page itself and click on an element to find out more about it. You can also click on the HTML tab to view the HTML and expand and collapse sections of it to see the structure of the page. Hovering over an element in the HTML panel will highlight it on the page; clicking on an element will let you find out more about it in the Style and Layout tabs of Firebug. (Firebug is an incredibly powerful tool that you really need to play with to fully appreciate. It's a completely non-destructive tool -- you can't hurt anything with it unless you try really, really hard -- so don't be afraid to click around and see what happens.)</li>
<li>Remember that these days, lots of page elements are built with Javascript rather than with straight HTML. <code>Ctrl-U</code> will show you only the HTML; Firebug will show you the "generated source," including any elements built with Javascript. Firebug also lets you look at the Javascript on a page, which can be helpful when you're trying to understand how something got there.
</li>
</ul>




<h3>POSH</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.456bereastreet.com/archive/200711/posh_plain_old_semantic_html/">Plain-old semantic HTML</a>. When you go to make a web page, write the simplest HTML you can, and use standard HTML elements whenever humanly possible. Start by creating HTML that represents the actual sections of the page -- header, navigation, sidebar, content, footer -- and give the elements names that say what they <em>are</em>, not where they go. When you think you're done, view the HTML in a browser, without CSS, and see if it makes sense. Then, <em>and only then</em>, open the browser's CSS editor and start styling the elements. See how far you can get without adding any design-related markup to your HTML. If you find yourself writing convoluted HTML or adding purely presentational markup, to make something work, it's time to reconsider your approach. Once you have a good stylesheet started, copy it to your text editor and continue working on it there.</p>

<h3>Strategies</h3>


<p>It helps to give yourself deadlines, even if they're imaginary. I've learned more about HTML, CSS and Javascript in the past 12 months than I learned in the three years before, and I think that's largely because deadlines have forced me to solve problems rather than pondering them.</p>

<p>Don't be afraid to do something less than perfectly; there can be value in just getting it done. I constantly look back at things I did three months ago -- let alone three years ago, and sometimes three weeks ago -- and I cringe when I think how differently I would do them today. But half the reason I know what I know now is precisely because I <em>didn't</em> know it then, and I learned it along the way. Understanding the building blocks of the web is an iterative process, and you'll do better if you remember that <strong>you cannot know everything you wish you knew</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using ems for font sizing in css]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/09/using-ems-for-font-sizing-in-css/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/09/using-ems-for-font-sizing-in-css</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A List Apart had a great article recently on <a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/howtosizetextincss/">using 'em' for CSS font-size declarations</a>, which served as great back-up for some conversations I'd been having among coworkers. (It turns out that people who didn't have a former life in print don't necessarily understand what an em is: a self-referential unit of font size measurement, equal to the height of the capital letter M. Back in the typesetting days, it was a unit for measuring space, especially horizontal space, in the form of an "em dash" (rendered now as <code>&amp;mdash;</code>) or an "em space." There was also a sister unit, the "en.")</p>

<p>Anyway: I just came across <a href="http://benjaminsterling.com/using-em-for-font-size-learning-on-the-go/">this post</a>, by someone trying to put ems into practice; at the end, he gets into tools for doing conversions from pixels to ems, and it struck a surprising nerve with me.</p>

<p>Here's the thing: While I can see how pixel conversion seems useful when you first make the switch from px to em, I think the whole point of using ems instead of pixels is to embrace the concept that, on the web, sizes are relative, not absolute. If you're focused on matching an absolute size in a mockup by converting pixels to ems, the chances seem good that you're dealing with a layout that wasn't intended to work with relatively sized text to begin with, and/or that your ultimate product won't work if the user makes a different decision than you about how they will consume it.</p>

<p>If you receive a Photoshop mockup where body copy is 10px tall, I think it's a tremendous waste of time to measure that 10px and convert it to ems -- 10px on my 1024x768 monitor is a far cry from 10px on my 1600x1200 monitor, nevermind on the HDTV sitting across the room.</p>

<p>When you're designing and styling text for the web, better to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Assume from the start that users will consume your site differently than you do.</li>
<li>Make decisions in your design, CSS and HTML that will consistently convey the content and hierarchy of your site, regardless of how it is consumed.</li>
<li>Assume that the user knows better than you what a good base text size is for them.</li>
<li>Use a reset styleheet — I like <a href="http://meyerweb.com/eric/thoughts/2007/05/01/reset-reloaded/">Eric Meyer's CSS Reset Reloaded</a> — to set everything to that base size.</li>
<li>Vary the sizes of elements <em>relatively</em> using ems.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standards for HTML emails?]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/07/standards-for-html-emails/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2007/12/07/standards-for-html-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a couple of attempts that ended not-so-well, I gave up on HTML emails. I advise people to work with someone who's an expert with them, or to at least <a href="http://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/">use templates that are known to work</a>, and then I wish them well. At a job interview I actually proclaimed my active dislike of HTML emails and general unwillingness to muck with them -- I'm not sure that went over so well. The news that <a href="http://www.campaignmonitor.com/blog/archives/2007/01/microsoft_takes_email_design_b.html">Outlook 2007 actually took a giant leap backwards in HTML support</a> seals the deal for me. Still, it's good to read that <a href="http://www.456bereastreet.com/archive/200712/the_email_standards_project_launches/">some people are trying to bring some sanity to the situation</a>. I wish them luck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
