<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: conferences | Adventures in JavaScript Development]]></title>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/categories/conferences/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-08T09:39:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://rmurphey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Murphey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Community Conferences]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/08/community-conferences/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T08:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/08/community-conferences</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2010, I helped put on the first TXJS. We sold our first tickets for $29, and
I think the most expensive tickets went for something like $129. We had about
200 people buy tickets, we had speakers like Douglas Crockford, Paul Irish, and
John Resig, and we had sponsors like Facebook and Google. Our total budget was
something like $30,000, and every out-of-town speaker had their travel and
accommodations paid for.</p>

<p>In May, O'Reilly Media is holding another JavaScript conference in San
Francisco, called FluentConf. I recently came to know that they are charging
$100,000 for top-tier sponsorships, and that they were offering a 10-minute
keynote as part of the package.</p>

<p>This turned my stomach, and not just because I believe it cheapens the
experience of attendees, who will pay hundreds of dollars themselves. What
really upset me was that a few weeks ago, I was approached to be on the speaker
selection committee of FluentConf, and that conversation led me to discover
that FluentConf would not be paying for speaker travel and accommodations. And
so the other day, I tweeted:</p>

<blockquote><p>conference #protip: save your money -- and your speaking skills -- for events that don't sell their keynotes for $100k</p></blockquote>

<p>Last night, I was at the Ginger Man in Austin, and I checked the Twitters,
discovering that Peter Cooper, one of the chairs of FluentConf, had replied to
a conversation that arose from that tweet:</p>

<blockquote><p>@rmurphey @tomdale If you're referring to Fluent, that is news to me.</p></blockquote>

<p>I will accept the weird fact that the co-chair of a conference didn't know its
speaking slots were for sale -- I gather that it is essentially a volunteer
role, and the co-chairs aren't necessarily in the driver's seat when it comes
to decisions like this. I let Peter know that, indeed, I had a PDF that
outlined all the sponsorship options.</p>

<p>This is the part where, in some alternate reality, a mutual understanding of
the offensiveness of this fact would have been achieved. What happened instead
was a whole lot of name-calling, misquoting, and general weirdness.</p>

<p>Here's the deal. Conferences can run their event however they want, and they
can make money hand over fist. They can even claim they are the giving
JavaScript developers "an event of their own," ignoring the existence of
the actual community-run JavaScript events that have been around for years now.  I
probably won't go to or speak at an event that makes money hand over fist, but
I don't have any problem with the existence of such events, or with people's
involvement with them.  However, when a conference is making money hand over
fist -- my back of the napkin calculations would suggest that FluentConf stands
to have revenues of well over a million dollars -- then that conference has no
excuse not to pay the relatively paltry costs associated with speaker travel
and accommodations.</p>

<p>A conference does not exist without its speakers. Those who speak at an event
-- the good ones, anyway -- spend countless hours preparing and rehearsing, and
they are away from home and work for days. While I do not discount the benefits
that accrue to good speakers, the costs of being a speaker are non-trivial --
and that's <em>before</em> you get into the dollar costs of travel and accommodations.</p>

<p>When an event is unwilling to cover even those hard costs -- nevermind the
preparation time and time away from work and home -- it materially affects the
selection of speakers.  It's even worse when those same conferences claim to
desire <a href="http://fluentconf.com/fluent2012/public/content/about#diversity">diversity</a>;
the people they claim to want so badly are the very people most likely to be
discouraged when they find out they have to pay their own way to the stage.</p>

<p>In the conversation last night, I made this point:</p>

<blockquote><p>when only the people who can afford to speak can speak, then only the people who can afford to speak will
speak.</p></blockquote>

<p>Amy Hoy responded with a criticism of community-run conferences:</p>

<blockquote><p>and when only ppl who can order a ticket in 3 seconds can afford to come, only ppl who can order a ticket in 3 seconds can come</p></blockquote>

<p>I know that getting tickets to the actual community-run events is hard, but
that is because the community-run events flat-out ignore the economics of
supply and demand, choosing instead to sell tickets at affordable prices even
if it means they will sell out in a heartbeat, leaving a boatload of potential
profit on the table. And yet those events -- JSConf, TXJS, and the like -- have
still figured out how to cover speaker costs and provide attendees and sponsors
with unforgettable experiences.</p>

<p>When an event with revenues exceeding a million dollars is unwilling to cover
those costs, while simultaneously selling speaking slots, I do not hesitate for
a moment to call that event out, and I do not hesitate to call
on <a href="http://fluentconf.com/fluent2012/public/content/about#commitee">respected members of the community</a> to sever
their ties with the event. I'm not embarrassed about it, and you can call me all
the names you want.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear conference organizer]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2010/08/24/dear-conference-organizer/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2010/08/24/dear-conference-organizer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
<p>Thank you for the invitation to speak at your conference, and your offer to pay my hotel and airfare in exchange.&nbsp;I notice that you are selling tickets for upwards of $1,500, in addition to hotel and travel costs. In exchange, you are hosting a three-day event, meals, a USB drive, a shirt, and a binder.</p>
<p>We need to talk, and not about the binder.</p>
<p>TXJS was a one-day conference with approximately a $30k budget -- some tickets cost a whopping $29, and the most expensive tickets were $109 -- and yet it managed to offer exactly what you're offering to me to its out-of-town speakers: hotel and travel. It had two nights of open-bar parties; a shuttle bus to get people to and from the amazing, eclectic, venue; catered breakfast and lunch; an open bar at the event itself; and a speaker and VIP brunch the following day. It also had some of the best JavaScript minds in the business on stage and in the audience, drawing people from around the country and beyond.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I hope you can appreciate the disconnect here. It's not so much that I want to get paid -- I have gladly and eagerly spoken at lower-cost conferences without even getting my hotel compensated -- as the fact that I know now that conferences just don't have to cost that much. When they do, it's hard to get on board with lending my name for free when the conference stands to have revenue of <em>hundreds of thousands of dollars</em> and I know I only needed revenue tens of thousands to put on an amazing event.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As a self-employed consultant, speaking at a conference has, at best, intangible benefit to me, and non-trivial costs. You and many other organizers can seem as though you assume the benefit is obvious, and the costs negligible. In fact, agreeing to a speaking engagement -- one that requires two non-working days for travel, a non-working day for speaking, and whatever prep time is required to actually put together my talk -- is a tough decision regardless of how much tickets cost, especially for someone without corporate backing or a product to promote. Call me selfish, but I need to be very clear that there's a benefit to me. A high-dollar conference likely to attract almost exclusively corporate-backed attendees with at best a peripheral relationship to my area of expertise is exactly the kind of conference where it's <em>not</em> clear what the benefit will be. Being away from home and work for three days, even in a nice hotel, just doesn't count.&nbsp;</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Finally: To all of the TXJS speakers, we heart you unbelievably and stand in awe that when we asked you to present at an event that had never existed before, each and every one of you said yes without batting an eye. I hope you know that we know that even with the open bar and the parties and the shuttle and the venue and all of it, we couldn't have had a conference without you.&nbsp;</p>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
