<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: client-side | Adventures in JavaScript Development]]></title>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/categories/client-side/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rmurphey.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-20T14:13:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rmurphey.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Murphey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on a (very) small project with Backbone and Backbone Boilerplate]]></title>
    <link href="http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/11/thoughts-on-a-very-small-project-with-backbone-and-backbone-boilerplate/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T21:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rmurphey.com/blog/2012/03/11/thoughts-on-a-very-small-project-with-backbone-and-backbone-boilerplate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I worked with <a href="http://documentcloud.github.com/backbone/">Backbone</a> and the
<a href="https://github.com/tbranyen/backbone-boilerplate">Backbone Boilerplate</a> for
the first time last weekend, putting together a small <a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/bvjs">demo app</a> for a presentation I gave last week at
BazaarVoice. I realize I'm about 18 months late to the Backbone party, here,
but I wanted to write down my thoughts, mostly because I'm pretty sure they'll
change as I get a chance to work with both tools more.</p>

<h2>Backbone</h2>

<p>Backbone describes itself as a tool that "gives structure to web applications,"
but, at the risk of sounding pedantic, I think it would be more accurate to say
that it gives you tools that can help you structure your applications. There's
incredibly little prescription about how to use the tools that Backbone
provides, and I have a feeling that the code I wrote to build my simple app
looks a lot different than what someone else might come up with.</p>

<p>This lack of prescription feels good and bad -- good, because I was able to use
Backbone to pretty quickly set up an infrastructure that mirrored ones I've
built in the past; bad, because it leaves open the possibility of lots of
people inventing lots of wheels. To its credit, it packs a lot of power in a
very small package -- 5.3k in production -- but a real app is going to require
layering a lot more functionality on top of it. Ultimately, the best way to
think of Backbone is as the client-side app boilerplate you'd otherwise have to
write yourself.</p>

<p>My biggest complaint about Backbone is probably how unopinionated it is about
the view layer. Its focus seems to be entirely on the data layer, but the view
is still where we spend the vast majority of our time. Specifically, I think
Backbone could take a page from Dojo, and embrace the concept of "templated
widgets", because that's what people seem to be doing with Backbone views
anyway: mixing data with a template to create a DOM fragment, placing that
fragment on the page, listening for user interaction with the fragment, and
updating it as required. Backbone provides for some of this, specifically the
event stuff, but it leaves you to write your own functionality when it comes to
templating, placing, and updating. I think this is a solveable problem without
a whole lot of code, and want to spend some time trying to prove it, but I know
I need to look into the Backbone Layout Manager before I get too carried away.</p>

<h2>Backbone Boilerplate</h2>

<p>This project from Tim Branyen was a life-saver -- it gave me an absolutely
enormous head start when it came to incorporating
<a href="http://requirejs.org/">RequireJS</a>, setting up my application directories, and
setting up a development server. It also included some great inline docs that
helped me get my bearings with Backbone.</p>

<p>There are a couple of ways I think the boilerplate could be improved, and I'd be
curious for others' opinions:</p>

<ul>
<li>The sample app includes the concept of "modules," which seem to be a single
file that include the models, collections, views, and routes for a ...
module. I don't love the idea of combining all of this into a single file,
because it seems to discourage smart reuse and unit testing of each piece of
functionality. In the app I created, I abandoned the concept of modules, and
instead broke my app into "components", "controllers", and "services". I
explain this breakdown in a bit more depth in the <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/rmurphey/bvjs">presentation I gave at BazaarVoice</a>. I'm not sure this is
the right answer for all apps, but I think modules oversimplify things.</li>
<li>The boilerplate includes a <code>namespace.js</code> file. It defines a namespace
object, and that object includes a <code>fetchTemplate</code> method. It seems this
method should only be used by views, and so I'd rather see something along
the lines of an enhanced View that provides this functionality. That's what I
did with the <a href="https://github.com/rmurphey/bvjs/blob/master/app/components/base.js">base component module</a>
in my sample app.</li>
<li>I'm super-glad to see Jasmine included in the test directory, but
unfortunately the examples show how to write Jasmine tests, not Jasmine tests
for a Backbone app. As a community, we definitely need to be showing more
examples of how to test things, and this seems like a good opportunity to
distribute that knowledge.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Overall</h2>

<p>I feel a little silly that I'm just now getting around to spending any time
with Backbone, and I know that I only scratched the surface, but I like what I
saw. I think it's important to take it for what it is: an uber-tiny library
that gets you pointed in the right direction. What I really want to see are
fuller-fledged frameworks that build on top of Backbone, because I think
there's a lot more that can be standardized beyond what Backbone offers. I'm
hoping to have a bit more time in April to dig in, and hopefully I can flesh
out some of these ideas into something useful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
